You're tuned to the drive on your 247
home of the black and gold Steelers
Nation radio.
Good afternoon, Steeler Nation, and
welcome back inside the Builtmore in
Phoenix, Arizona for our final day of
league meetings coverage here on the
drive. Wesler and Matt Williamson with
you. It's another bonus threehour show
and we are off and running. Matt, we are
>> rolling. Morning starting great.
>> We are on cloud9 right now for a let me
say a trio of different reasons. Okay.
>> So many fir first of all
>> I don't know how you narrow it down to
three.
>> First of all, Mike McCarthy's uh
breakfast this morning. We have we have
the audio and and all the good
information and details from that that
we're going to actually play for you
here uh in just a few minutes. You and I
had a lovely time at the annual league
owners uh meeting dinner last night.
Some
>> pretty impressive affair. incredible,
incredible food and who's who of the
football world.
>> And then we finally here this morning
got our Nike swag bags, our giveaways.
We got a bag from Nike. We got a bag
from New Era. We got a bag from
Fanatics. I got a couple NFL hoodies for
my daughters. We got probably $2,000
worth of merch stuff.
>> I mean, just getting it on the plane is
is going to be a an adventure. You know,
the puzzle pieces to build the build it
>> and lovely breakfast. We get to do this
show. I wouldn't narrow it down to
three. And the weather's fine as could
be. It's going to be a big Steeler day
starting with Coach McCarthy's
breakfast. I mean, we got a lot more AFC
and Steeler stuff to talk about and
>> and then uh back on a plane tomorrow.
>> Exactly. Right. It all happens very
fast, but it's been a lot of fun. And
yeah, that dinner last night was
certainly something by my estimation.
Two sushi stations, two steak stations.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> There was salmon there.
>> Salmon and seafood and stuff, too. Uh
then there was a burger truck. There was
what am I forgetting? A pasta station as
well too.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and about, you know, I think four
different open bars with a bunch of
different crazy cocktails and fun drinks
and all different kind.
>> A very classy band that was playing.
Yep. With a really good lead singer. Uh
and it was so it was a lot of fun last
night. The NFL's uh who's who last night
there at the uh uh at the uh annual
league meeting owners uh dinner party.
>> Yeah. and kind of paint the scene. It's
pretty cool. Like you go through the
resort a little bit and then you go and
and there's like a huge bar area with
all kinds of water features and that's
like the lower level. And as the night
went on, it seemed like a lot of the
more recognizable folks were down there,
you know, just doing their own thing. I
mean, no one's swinging from chandeliers
or anything, but I mean, they're having
a good time. And then, like you
mentioned, you go up to the next level
and it's almost everything on the right
is the same as everything on the left.
Okay. like start with sushi, start with,
you know, like everything parallels each
other. Big band in the middle, big area
in the middle,
>> like a big fancy wedding reception.
>> And then we went to the left and we were
calling that Kitty Land because there
was a lot of like things for kids. There
were ponies over there. That was crazy.
>> You could make friendship bracelets and
and all and selfie stations, all that
different kind of stuff.
>> Yeah. And an amazing where we spent some
time was this particular bar area were
making smoked drinks. There was only
four drinks to pick from. One was an
espresso martini, which was not my bag.
You were doing some sort of tequila
smoked something.
>> Basically a watermelon smoked watermelon
margarita. It was in as refreshing of
you could imagine. Yeah.
>> And we were doing like smoked Manhattans
and you know Yeah, it was great. And I
didn't realize till the end you got to
pick which wood they would smoke with.
Did you catch that? Cherry or something
else? I think. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I'm not
sure I could tell the difference, but
hey, they were going down good and we
had a good time.
>> They sure they sure did. We got some
customized bag tags that the NFL gave
out, too. Uh I got to talk with,
>> you know, maybe, you know, if you if you
list the uh distinguished WVU alumni. Uh
I think,
>> of course, your bag tag is WV.
>> I think Well, that's my initials. What
do you want me to do about it? I think
uh I slot in maybe at number two right
behind this Pat McAfee guy. I don't know
if you've heard of him, but he hosts a
national show on ESPN.
>> Yeah, you went and chatted with him a
little bit, right?
>> Talked to talked to McAfee a little bit.
We've got a bunch of mutual connections.
He's been on the the WVU show that I do
a few times. I do a show with one of his
former teammates, Owen Schmidt, who
played in the NFL for a few years for
the Eagles and the Seahawks and the
Raiders.
>> They were teammates, you said, right?
>> They were teammates at WV. Yeah. So, so
that was fun. Um,
>> had to be a heck of a teammate. I I just
remember him as a draft prospect cuz he
was like a 265 Patrick Ricard fullback
type dude, you know?
>> Absolutely. Mashing face masks. So,
yeah. So, we got to uh we got to hang
out with some of our our friends in the
Pittsburgh media. We got to hang out
with some people in the national media.
An incredible dinner. a really cool site
to see and then today kind of being the
um the cherry on top of all this. You
know,
>> this be our last show from here, but
right
>> in our in our last show from here. So,
here's what we're going to do because
we've got a beefy uh Mike McCarthy media
availability from the head coach's
breakfast this morning to play for you
on the other side. So, we're going to
take a shorter first segment here so we
have time to listen to that in its
entirety and react to it on the back
end. Just getting started here on this
Tuesday, our final day of coverage here
in Arizona for the NFL annual league
meetings. Wesler, Matt Williamson. It is
the drive. Steelers Nation Radio on the
Steelers Audio Network.
>> What's up NFL fans? The NFL draft is
finally here. And while you might not
know who your team is drafting this
year, you do know your watch party's
number one pick. Bud Light. The clean,
crisp taste that has all the scouts
talking. Guess that's why it's been the
group's go-to draft beer season after
season. Be sure to order a round for the
table before your teams on the clock.
Bud Light. Easy to drink, easy to enjoy.
Enjoy responsibly. Andheiser Bush, Bud
Light Beer, St. Louis, Missouri.
>> You're tuned to the drive on your 247
home of the black and gold Steelers
Nation Radio.
Back inside the Builtmore here in
Arizona. It is our final day of league
meeting coverage here on Steelers Nation
Radio. The Steelers Audio Network.
Wesler and Matt Williamson with you.
It's another bonus three-hour edition of
the drive. And of course, uh today the
AFC head coaches having their media
availability breakfast. Uh Matt was was
making the funny joke about how they,
you know, they kind of battle out the
AFC and the NFC coaches. Who gets to
have it on Monday versus Tuesday? You'd
much rather do Monday after the party
last night
>> because no one wants to do it after the
party last night and it's early,
>> but it was the AFC.
>> You had a great point though, like the
Super Bowl champ got get got Monday this
year. I wonder if that's always a thing.
>> It should be like the Major League
Baseball All-Star game. Yeah. Yeah. Like
whoever whoever wins the Super Bowl,
their conference gets the Monday slot
and the other gets the Tuesday slot.
>> But well, there's 10 new head coaches
this year though. a bunch of new
>> someone like Harbaugh's like my my side
didn't win the Super Bowl but I get to I
get I reap the benefits I switch
conference
>> lots of new head coaches this year
across the league uh plenty in the AFC
North three of them and of course the
most important one our very own Mike
McCarthy who is doing this uh owners
meeting for the first time not for the
first time for him but the first time as
the head coach of the Pittsburgh
Steelers and here's what he had to say
at his availability this morning
>> morning
to get the conversations there going
>> good.
You know, I was telling Bert this on the
way over here. Um 2006 was my first
uh first time doing this and and the
first question was about a veteran
quarterback whether he was going to come
back or not. So, it was a big deja vu,
but no, it's it's going good. Um it's
been very positive and we'll just
continue to talk. So, we talk regularly.
Were you confident then and are you the
same level of confident now?
>> That's a great question. Uh it was a
different tone then because I was just a
youngster and and the questions your
your questions are a lot more were very
polite compared to the way the questions
were asked back then. So, but uh yeah,
I'm I'm confident, but at the end of the
day, it's a personal decision. So, uh I
think we're in a good space.
>> Mike, you were kind of alluding to this
yesterday. what depending on the city
you're playing, cold weather Green Bay,
cold weather Pittsburgh as opposed to
warm weather Dallas is a type of
quarterback,
bigger, stronger, more physical type of
quarterback necessary. You know what I
mean?
>> Well, I I just think it's part of your
preparation, you know, and it's it's
part of your uh it's part of your
planning as far as what your system's
going to look like. Uh because the end
of the day, you know, the most important
games are in December, December and
January. and and to be able to play in
those games in an out outdoor, you know,
it requires to play a certain way and uh
and that's was always evident in my time
in Green Bay and yeah, there's, you
know, there's things that uh you do for
the surface, you know, the type of shoes
you make sure your guys wear, all all
those little details. Um, those are the
things that I think about and even when
we're talking about player profiles
yesterday, I think that's that's where
the discipline of trying to stay true to
that type of player is important in the
outdoor climates in my opinion.
>> How how similar do you anticipate your
offense being in Pittsburgh to what you
are doing in Green Bay, especially if
Aaron does? Um
I mean similar as in I mean it's going
to be the same offense uh structurally
as far as the beliefs uh the principles
of the philosophical approach the depth
in the details but you know it's very
important in my opinion systematically
if you draft a player that has unique
talents and you say he can't fit he
doesn't fit my system. I've always felt
that you got to take a look at your
system. So, we got to be able to have
room, you know, we got to have a big
enough arrow. So, when Omar and the
personnel, we sit in there and we
decide, you know, to draft these these
young men that that we have we have a
place, you know, for them. Um,
everything all right.
You good? Okay. All right.
That was funny. Um, so,
>> oh, is that priorities? I get it. Yeah,
I get it. Okay. Okay, where the hell
were we?
>> Oh god.
>> System.
>> Yeah, fin system. So, you know, be
systematic with your players. So, so we
all run similar plays. Um, you know,
concept teach. It's just how you coach
them. You know, the the details. Um, you
know, certain receivers have different
skill set to how they run an option
route. So, you know, you got to tie that
option route to the quarterback's feet.
So all those things we'll be probably
closer to the offense in Dallas than
probably what we did in Green Bay. Um so
for for comparable
>> does that similarities and and that kind
of continuity at all help maybe give you
a little bit more flexibility with
Aaron's decision-m timeline that he has
some familiarity with those concepts in
Green Bay.
>> Well, if he was sitting here, I think he
would echo the same thing. The
quarterback room's going to be coached
the same way whether he's in there or
he's not. It's, you know, you coach to
the lead lead player because if you're
going to if you're going to build your
if you take the passing game, if you're
truly going to be tied to the to the
discipline and the footwork and the
teachings of of how that position plays
and it's coordinated with the perimeter,
um you have to get they all have to be,
you know, synchronized. So that that
part won't change. And uh so that that's
why I mean you know we we're we're
always looking to I'd have five
quarterbacks if you if you could you
know and I I think it's something the
league should consider but uh you know I
I don't think you're going to have
enough quarterbacks in your building to
train. So it's it's it's it's the
starting point of the offense and and
that's the way it's always been and
that's the way we'll be in Pittsburgh.
Oh, definitely. I I I love I love the
fact that their play styles emulate each
other. So, that's what I was real
excited about with Rico, you know,
having to work with Rico. Uh, a big
thing that I I I think is very important
for a running back, the first question I
always ask in the evaluation process,
can he play all three all three downs?
You know, cuz, you know, we all want
four down players. I mean, if you're,
you know, you're looking to build a
scope of, you know, particularly the
running back position and linebacker
positions, you know, for value, but uh,
you know, these guys both can play all
three downs. And that's that's
important. That's and it's real
important for a play caller because, you
know, you want to push you want to push
the envelope, you know, get in and out
of uh, you know, personnel groups. You
also want to be able to stay on the
field, right? You know, go right from
second down to third down, go right from
third down to fourth down and no huddle
type things. And so having backs that
don't have to come out of the game on
third down, that's that's that's
something that I I put a lot of value
in, you know, and I and I feel that we
got two guys we can just go play
tomorrow with. And uh, and I'm excited
about those guys.
at safety. Now you got three guys
safety.
How does it affect? How do you see guys?
>> Yeah, we're going we're staying right
down the same path. You know, we're
talking about player flexibility. Uh
that's really the first conversation I
have with Jaylen. you know, you know,
looking at our defense part from the
offensive perspective, whether you're a
pass rusher or a dynamic, you know,
secondary player, you know, if you can
line up at safety, nickel, dime, and and
jump out the corner in a matchup
situation, there's tremendous value in
that. So, and and that's why, you know,
Brisker, the ability to play multiple
positions, and it's going to be the same
way in the draft. We're having these
same conversations because 17 games is
real. You know, 16 games is a long
season. You know, I you know, you
remember when we went from 14 to 16. So,
position flex is critical probably in
the offensive line more than any
position in football. I mean, I I
haven't had an offensive line, you know,
if you look at the statistic of five the
starts of the five same offensive
lineman, the number of games they start
and how it equates to winning. It's been
going on in our league for decades. So,
play player position flexibility is
something that I that I put a lot of
value in.
Brian Angelico
plays how you guys
>> I mean Angelico Brian is a outstanding
football coach. Um he's he's the
offensive coordinator. Coordinating is
probably the toughest job in the NFL. Um
you know I think you know going along
with the play calling. So to have
someone that's uh like Brian that I'm
aligned with. We've worked we worked
together before. Um you know he's got a
ton of experience. Uh he's a great
teacher. He's a glue guy. uh his
knowledge base is as high as anybody
you'd sit down and talk football with.
He's been in different systems. So, I
mean, he'll do the everyday coordinator
things and and I'll do it alongside with
him cuz we have to be connected. Um, and
you know, and so we we spend a lot of
time like I you know, we spend a lot of
time talking after the fact, you know,
but cuz he needs to keep, for instance,
what I'm saying is we have a meeting
schedule that's set and then um, you
know, we start at 7:30 and the meeting
goes well, I may get pulled out of
there. So my ability to jump in and out
of there, he has to be able to keep
going. So I've done this before and so
that's the way it works. And and I just
to think that for me to have a
confidence I have in him in year one
shows what I think of him because I you
know normally that's something you
evolve to just enjoy going play. Do you
ever think about just
somebody else or something?
>> Oh man way too many cameras for a fun
answer here. Um just uh no I I think the
think calling plays you know jobs
responsibilities you know it's everybody
in in coaching operations you know we
look at everybody that we you know bring
into our building you know everybody has
talents you know everybody has
experience and when you put it all
together you know in in this particular
responsibility we feel it's the best
thing for our football team.
this time around.
>> Yeah, I think it's unique in a number of
ways. A, you know, because I've been in
the league a long time, um, you have a
you have a a lot of candidates. The the
Western Pennsylvania NFL
connection is real. Um, there's a
there's a lot of people that are
disappointed that not having the
opportunity to to be, you know, with
with the Steelers. I clearly understand
that. So, that was a challenge. Um, I've
always looked at the, you know, the
hiring process, you know, diversity is
something I've always had in the
forefront of my mind, whether it's, you
know, um, player, former player, non
former player, you know, um, small
college guy. I I I always wanted my
staff to have a level of experience.
Then I had I wanted middle, you know,
like a middle class that can grow to
that position. And I always wanted to
develop young guys. I've always viewed
the coaching staff very similar to the
to the locker room. So, I I've always
looked at that. If you look at the three
staffs that I've hired in Green Bay,
Dallas, and now Pittsburgh, you you
you'll see the diversity in those staffs
because, you know, it's locker rooms.
It's everybody talks about culture and
and the needle of growth is something
that NFL locker rooms are very unique
and I've always tried to emulate that in
developing a coaching staff. While
you're talking about coaching staff, I'm
curious, how much do you plan to be
involved in like all aspects, both sides
of the ball? And how much will there be
autonomy for Patrick Graham to take
command of of that side and the defense?
>> Yeah, just just doing this for quite
some time and and really my first
experience where I felt I was able to
get into the rhythm was with Dom Capers.
Dom was we were together I want to say
nine years 10 years in Green Bay and
Dom's an early morning guy. So, you
know, we'd always have that block of
time, you know, from like, you know,
5:00 a.m. to 6:15 and set his day and
keep keep me in the loop of what's going
on. And then also, you know, at the end
of the night, cuz, you know, it's off
you have to be if you're going to call
the plays, you got to be in the room.
You got to be in the decision. I have to
be in that quarterback room. So, and you
can't be you can't be in all those
places at once and they it's ridiculous
to try. So, um but you know, I've known
Patrick for quite some time. Um he knows
how I feel about the history of this
defense. I mean, this system's been Dom
Capers, Bill Cower put this system in
1992. You know, Mike Tom has done a
great job carrying it forward. So, we're
looking to build off of what's what's in
place. You know, we're not we're not
throwing away everything and starting
over. So when our players get there,
they'll see the the variation that we're
teaching in what the beliefs are.
>> Mike, a year removed from Dallas. How do
you look back on that on your tenure
there?
>> Oo. Um,
great experience. I think just like
anything, especially the last couple
days, the people, you know, just some
great people there. Really enjoyed
working with him. Was uh Jerry, I mean,
I got to see him u on Sunday. So, um I I
miss him in a lot of ways, you know. So,
he's uh um I I think I've heard all the
stories 10 times, so I think I'm good on
the story storytelling. But no, that the
family and and just the way um you know,
they treat the people working there.
That's that's definitely something I
miss. But, um you know, I'm I'm I'm
thankful for all my experiences. Uh the
start was was wild. I mean, the pandemic
year was, you know, something I, you
know, I look back on it, I didn't I
didn't I felt like I could I could have
did a better job. Uh, we just had a lot
of balls in the air. Um, but I thought
once we got the program going, you know,
I thought we kind of hit our stride
during the second year. And, um, I I
really like the direction of the team,
you know, you know, when I left there. I
like the draft classes that we put
together. So, I have I have nothing but
uh, great things to say about my
experience in Dallas.
>> Mike, broader question, but you've been
in this league a long time. When a team
transitions from a 4-3 defense to a 34
defense, what does it take from a
coaching standpoint, from training the
players that have been there and from
getting the rights of people in there
for the new
>> Well, the biggest thing is the profiles
and really today, you know, it's not
like you're playing a pure 3, four or
43. It's more about, you know, which
techniques you're living in. I'm, you
know, if you play the even techniques,
you know, are you are you going to play
a flat stance, you know, with your D
lineman? So, the body type is very
important. You don't want to be playing
flat stance with guys that don't have
the length to do it. So, that's that's
where the the profile part of it is has
been the biggest change. I went through
that in in Green Bay in '09, uh, when we
we we switched from the 43 or 08, I
guess it was. Yeah, 09. And so, um, it's
that's the part you have to get right.
>> Can you do it from a personnel
standpoint in one offseason or does it
take a couple years to get the right
profiles in there?
>> To be honest, it really depends what's
available. I mean, you like to, you
know, you like to and it's a couple
position, but at the end of the day, I
mean, you know, and the league's is
trending back more towards some more
base defense, but it's still a primarily
a subdefense league and, you know, and
that's as we know is a is really
primarily fourman fronts. So,
>> Mike, one of the guys that you retained
on staff from Mike Tom was Tom Hart. We
know you have familiarity with him from
Green Bay, but what is it that you like
about him and the way that he works with
the quarterbacks? You know, Tom Tom made
such an impression on on me in his short
time um in Green Bay. You know, him and
Aaron, that was when you you were still
able to have the quarterback school
where you'd start in the middle of March
and and uh and he he was he was awesome.
You know, he was a sponge. No surprise
at all that he went into coaching. I
mean, I he was a natural fit. So, oh,
you know, I think his what he's put
together, his career, his career is is
exciting and and I think Tom has a a
tremendously bright future. So, um, he
would he would he would have definitely
been a candidate even if he wasn't
already there. I So, um, I'm excited to
to be, you know, reconnected with Tom
and and looking forward to, you know,
getting that quarterback room right and
and having him on it like I was given
that chance a long time ago. So, yeah,
Tom Tom's an excellent coach. Excellent
coach. You know, he's been a head coach.
Um, you know, he's been out of football.
I mean, he's got a such a unique
background. You know, the only thing I,
you know, I don't like about him, he's
from Cleveland. So, but we have we work
through that. So,
>> how much does it help a guy like Will
Howard, a young guy to have that
continuity in the position coaches he
>> big time. I mean, uh, that quarterback
coach is so important. I mean, if Aaron
Rogers and you look at guys in their
careers, great quarterbacks pretty much
usually have a great relationship with
their their quarterback coach,
particularly their their first one. you
know, that's a those are foundation
moments, foundation opportunities
um that that you know, like Troy Aman, I
look at the way he he he still talks
about North Turner, you know, just so I
mean that you you see it over and over
and over again. So, um and and we'll
we'll have that with Tom.
>> Mike, at what point does timing become
an issue with Aaron Rogers decision? And
are you and he in relative agreement on
that title?
>> Yeah, I'm not going to really get into
timelines. So, we're we're in constant
communication. Um, talked to them last
night. So, I mean, so we're um we're
we're in a good space and and we're just
continue to work through it.
>> Did you tell him last night questions
about him?
>> No, I didn't.
>> He says hello. So,
>> is he going to show up here and answer
them for himself?
>> We're good. All right. We're good on air
and questions. Okay.
>> Now that you're a couple of months in,
what is your sense of being able to
build a championship contender? This
team's been in a little bit of a rut,
which is why you're in this position.
>> Well, I I I would say the team's in a
rut. The team won the division last
year. So, it's a playoff football team.
Uh I viewed I viewed the team that way
as a fan last year. You know, I was able
to sit back and and I and I watched the
you know, the Steelers, the Cowboys, and
the Packers. I try to watch all three
teams as a fan just because of the
connection with the three teams. Um, you
know, I thought they had some really
good moments and I was just talking to
Nick Herrering about this. I I really
like the vibe of the team coming down
the stretch. I thought they were coming
together and he he was he was telling me
about we were talking about the locker
room. I said, "I thought you guys
really, you know, were positioned to
make a run." And that's is we've seen it
time and time again. If you can, you
know, play good football and maybe, you
know, your your lows are not as, you
know, too low and the e and flow of your
team is consistent, you can hit that
December stretch, you can go on a
playoff run. So that's my opinion of
last year. Um, so yeah, and and you have
changed. Yeah. Now you turn the page,
it's a, you know, new coaching staff.
It'll be a new system of operation. So
it's important for us to connect. Uh,
winning's a huge part of the Pittsburgh
Steeler culture. Um,
you know, I'm I'm I'm bringing a winning
process to Pittsburgh and and um we plan
on winning. So,
>> how involved or hands-on do you in the
draft process and has that increased as
you become more established? And how
different is it the three teams you
>> It's been a challenge this year. I love
it. I love that. This is uh I'd say the
most involved of the three teams. Um,
it's been, you know, I think that's just
probably has gone with the arc of my
career, too. Um, you know, Green Bay was
a, you know, Ted was was established
general manager. I was a rookie and so,
but I I loved our relationship and how
we did personnel then. Um, you know,
Ted's one thing with me was always um,
you know, I'll never give you a player
that you don't want cuz you know, it's
not going to you know, there's just no
sense in that. that was, you know, how
he treated those those moments. Dallas,
the coaches were very involved. Um, it
was a very coach friendly process there.
Um, and it's probably similar to to
Pittsburgh. I mean, our coaching staff's
very involved in and it's been uh it's
been difficult to be honest with you
because year one's year one. I mean,
there's just so much to do. You know,
I'm a old school believer. You go back
and we put page one of the playbook in.
We talk about the huddle, put the ball
in play cadence. we we you know we don't
just take the old playbook. I mean it'
been very easy for me to just to put the
playbook on the middle of the table and
say this is what we're running. That's
not what we did. Um I'm trying to keep
some of the terminology for the
offensive players. We've been able to do
that for the defensive players because
of the history of the defense. So we're
you know we we are trying to um keep
some things that work for us as a
coaching staff that that are in place
there and just try to keep the the
newness to a minimum. So, um, and that's
timeconuming is my point. So, uh, the
coaching staff is they they've been
grinding. So, uh, this next month is
going to be it's it's going to be a lot
of fun, but we'll basically split our
day between trying to get the players
acclimated with our systems and, uh,
we'll be in the draft meetings, you
know, in the afternoons
>> when you left Dallas.
John, how do you
>> looking forward to working with those
guys? you know, it's particularly, you
know, I I'm I'm
aware of their past experience, but you
know, I mean, it's this is like a
Catholic operation. You know, you go to
say three hill Marys and priest press,
everybody's got a clean slate, so let's
let's just get to work. I mean, all and
I you have to do that with young guys.
So, um, and that, so I'm looking forward
to, you know, I understood what
happened, you know, with him on special
teams and so I've heard all that, but
he's he's a young man that obviously,
you know, his his draft value was, you
know, what with the what do we think of
him and so I can't really answer till I
till I get my hands on him and, you
know, but I'm going to challenge him to
be a three down player, you know,
challenge him to be special teams
player. And so all the all those things
are are part of being a young running
back in this league, especially with
with the two guys in front of him.
>> Mikey, I'm sorry. Talk about the uh Bill
Coward, Don Caper's blueprint. Where was
it fairly identical and where what you
have seen?
>> Blueprinting.
>> I I mean, you're talking about the 34
defense. You see, okay, you know.
>> Well, the base is the same, you know. I
mean, tight dog rush, you know, or tight
was a dog rush once now. um tight dog
10. So cuz you know cover one and cover
10's there's a different variation. So
but it's the same it's the same it's the
same call you know and and that was
Dom's lead call for as long as I've
known him and Kevin Green that's all you
ever wanted to run you know. So, um, you
know, so that's that that base is still
there, you know, so when we put in the
base defense, you know, the tight front
will go in first. Uh, the form of the
under, you know, will come off of that.
So, there'll be a very similar teaching
progression of how things are things put
in. Dom Capers is is as detailed as a
coach that that I've ever worked with.
You know, I used to used to worry about
our salary cap. Um because Dom would
spend so much money on highlighters. You
know, I was always worried about us
going over the cap because, you know, he
he would uh or office supplies went
through the roof, you know what I mean?
So, but uh no, but Dom was Dom was
awesome to work with. So, there'll be a
lot of similar and it's really, you
know, what TA did too. I mean, so I mean
I you could always see the the blueprint
of the past has always been here in my
opinion against those guys. Mike, you
guys traded for Michael Pitman. How do
you kind of envision he and DK working
together and what was it that you liked
about him and admired
>> position flex? You know, I do prefer the
bigger targets. You know, I think it's
common sense. I mean, you look at
completion percentage, you you want your
quarterback north of 70%, you want the
ball distributed. You know, you want 55,
you know, combination of completions and
rushes to be 55 plus a game. So, those
are things that I I believe in of how
you're going to play on offense. And,
uh, that's why, you know, tight ends,
big tight ends that target, you know,
it's easier to throw these passes than
the ones out there. So, um, those are
common sense uh, practices that I that
I'm that I'm, you know, I keep keep in
touch with. So I the the bigger
receivers outdoor climate. Um the
ability to to be to be nasty in first
and second down in a run game because
you know we we sat through the meetings
here at uh was that Sunday and they
talked about the big plays you know the
statistics I don't know if everybody
here you get copies of all that but the
the big the big play numbers are down.
So I mean that's something as a coach
you're always looking to try to enhance
your your big plays opportunities on
first and second down. It obviously
comes off off of the run game. So bigger
receivers definitely help in that area.
>> When you left
the opportunity to put big guys into
there, what are the sort of things that
we look for aside from the physical
traits and maybe what are some things
that you personally consider a red flag
that scare you away from a guy when
you're talking about?
Well, I mean, every place I've worked,
you know, whether it's a,
you know, whether it's an orange dot or,
you know, you know, EQ grade, you know,
your emotional quotient, every how you
look at that, uh, everybody has a
history. Um, you know, and now with the
with the age of the of the prospects
coming in, you know, you got more 24,
25, 26 year old. So, so there's more to
look at. But yeah, you're you're looking
at you're looking for people that that
fit your culture, you know, and that
that that fit Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.
So, um that's that's definitely a big
part of the conversation. So, um I' I've
never really felt um as a head coach of
a football team that you never had
enough talent. I mean, I I I've always
feel that there's enough there. Uh it's
really the connection, the emotional
connection, uh that that's how you win
championships. So, so you're definitely
looking for quality people without a
doubt.
>> When you left Alison, do you think you'd
get another chance or did you think that
was it?
>> Um, yeah. I I you know, I have
confidence in my abilities, but but I'm
also realistic. Uh, you know, growing up
to sit here and say that uh I dreamt in,
you know, in my my fifth grade diaries,
I I wrote down I wanted to be the head
coach of three NFL teams. That's that's
not true. Um, but no, I I I've been
super blessed um to for the people that
I grew up around, starting with the way
I was raised, uh, the NFL coaches that
um that I was able to train up, the
University of Pittsburgh coaching staff
that I was on. So, uh, you know, so I
have a lot of confidence in my education
and my experience through the league and
and and feel that, you know, I I would
have a lot to offer to a club. But I'm
also um you know, I've been around the
block a few times and I'm very
comfortable in my own skin and um and
I'm not going to lie to you, I I love
being a full-time dad. I've been able to
do it twice, you know, 19 and this past
year and um the year off was was very
very rewarding for me. So, and that's
why this this opportunity, I mean, just
the way it came about, you know, so um I
I had to I had to come back. I mean, it
was it was a if there's ever a
no-brainer, you know, opportunity in my
lifetime, this this was it. And so,
yeah, but definitely I I have I have a
lot of confidence in my ability.
>> Why do you think the NFL is skewed
toward young offensive coaches? And what
do you think about someone like Monkey
getting his first chance at 60? You
know, I I can only go based off
experience, you know, being being a
young offensive coach at the at a time
coming into the league and
understanding, you know, you know, the
way the league was trending. Um,
our game's about trends, you know,
playing in coaching, scheme, you know,
health and safety. So, I mean, it's
Yeah. So, I now been able to to
interview in a number of places. I mean,
everybody's looking for something
different and and what I have learned is
it's got to fit, you know, so whether
it's offense, defense, I still think
people win. You win with people. I I
don't I don't believe in he has to be
that kind of guy. So, guy could be a
hell of an offensive coach, but he might
not fit in one organization as good as
he fits in another organization. I I I
think that's real, you know, and that's
been my that's been my experience.
That's my opinion.
>> Guys, two more here. We got to get them
going.
>> You mentioned earlier that you kind of
view the coaching staff.
You want to throw young guys
just that kind of what you were talking
about and what's your relationship like?
>> Yeah, Brian, you know, I'm going to
consider Bri Brian just he needed a he
needed just a reset that year as a
consultant. I I thought I thought a he
was a a tremendous asset for us. Um, you
know, we had Ben Mack do it the year
before, so to have that level of coach
in that position was a true benefit. And
and I and I think he really enjoyed it.
You know, he enjoyed being on the
defensive side of the ball. So, it was
it was it was an able for opportunity
for him to to look through that lens for
a year and he gave Dan Quinn great
input. So, I mean, it was awesome to do
that. But, he just needed a reset for
his family and frankly, I just went
through the same thing in 19. I thought
it was I thought it was really good for
him, you know, personally, really good
for his family and and look what it did.
It springboarded him right back in as an
offensive coordinator. I thought he did
a great job for us and uh so well
deserving of his opportunity in Dallas.
So, and um if there's ever been a guy
that's ready, it's it's definitely Brian
Sh.
>> Mike, you've talked on a number of about
just what what you like about Will
Howard. Where will we need to develop
the most to reach his goal? I think the
biggest thing with Will and it's
probably, you know, consistent with
young quarterbacks, they got to win from
the pocket. At the end of the day, you
know, nine 10 games a year are going to
come down to the two minutes really.
That's that's what the stats tell you.
That's the way we train. So, his ability
to win from the pocket cuz I think he
has everything else. I mean, I people
get caught up on, you know, what round
he went in, but if I was drafting
players uh that year, he wouldn't have
been around in the fifth or sixth round.
I mean, I I I I valued him higher than
that based off Kansas State. And man, he
just I thought he jumped jumped out of
the TV set during the college playoffs.
I mean, I I mean, what is there not to
like about the guy? So, um I think he's
definitely a real prospect as a starting
quarterback. I I I believed that when he
came out. I I don't you know, so you
could talk about his strong, you could
talk about some things throwing the
ball. Um I think there's a lot of a lot
of growth with his feet, you know, like
a lot of these guys that and the the
challenge I see in college football,
it's so scheme heavy and they're running
these quarterbacks and their and their
and their schemes are diverse. There's
not a lot of training in the footwork.
So throwing the ball and you got the
best guy that probably has ever done it
in Aaron Rogers. I mean, you look at the
way Aaron throws. I mean, just watch his
feet, you know, watch the ground force,
you know, explosion that comes up
through his feet, through his hips into
his throwing motion. So, and um so there
my point is there's room for development
there. So, um I think there's a lot to
work with Will. I'm excited. I'm excited
to work with
So, we just heard from Mike McCarthy
lengthy head coaches media availability
today. It's a it's almost like a
>> I don't want to say a breakfast setting
because it's not like everyone's eating
but
>> Right. But it's in the morning. It's in
the morning around breakfast time and
they all sit in a ballroom around big,
you know, circular tables and everyone
can kind of local media, national media
get in there and ask a bunch of
questions and there is obviously a bunch
that the Steelers head coach Mike
McCarthy had to say there that we want
to discuss further.
>> And Matt, I think of course you have to
start at the top with all the latest on
Aaron Rogers.
>> Yeah. Saying that he actually talked to
him last night. Uh that they've that
he's spoken with Aaron Rogers quote
every couple of days. Uh they talk about
life, they talk about football, they
talk about what's going on at the
facility. I quote, "I would just say
he's in a very positive space. We'll
just continue to engage in our
conversations." He was also asked about
if he'd be comfortable with Aaron Rogers
missing OTAAS. Said he didn't want to
get into any hypotheticals. Quote, "I
truly understand why you're asking the
question. I'm just focused on my next
conversation with him." End quote.
>> Yeah. And that all sound, again, I don't
want to jump to conclusions, but that
sure sounds like there's a really good
chance Aaron Rogers is going to be the
starting quarterback. And the
communication
>> actually surprised me to the was to that
level, you know? I mean, we don't need
to narrow it down. We talk every two
days or whatever, you know, but I mean
it obviously they're in pretty constant
communication. And that's not even
mentioning how often Tom talks to him or
Cam Hayward even for that matter. I
mean, they're friends. I mean that that
they could be talking about their kids
or whatever or Omar or whatever. Like I
don't think they're running by personnel
decisions like do you approve of Michael
Pitman, Aaron Rogers? You know, I don't
think that kind of stuff's happening.
But the um the constant communication I
thought really stood out because
there's obviously massive mutual
interest here.
>> Totally. And that's where this all
continues to go. It is, you know, we're
not going to get an answer until we get
an answer, but all the tea leaves uh
continued to come up that this is the uh
>> the future for the Pittsburgh Steelers.
We're a little distracted here because
Emil from video just brought over a
Gatorade can. Yeah,
>> canned Gatorade. That's
>> Look at this. I haven't seen one of
these, I don't think, since I was like
10.
>> That's rare right there. That's like
pulling a Barry Bonds rookie card.
That's the That's the That's the That's
the good stuff right there.
>> I'm going to have to try it. It's been a
while.
>> I'm going to have I'm going to need a
couple of those. Gator Gatorade out of a
can is just hidden.
>> Might have to grab one for tomorrow
morning, too.
>> So, that was the uh that was the
biggest, you know, I mean, just in terms
of the general conversation, Matt. But,
you know, a couple things that also
really stood out to me. Maybe the the
quote of the day.
>> Couple things did. Yeah.
>> Quote of the day from Mike McCarthy. You
got to love this when asked about Caleb
Johnson, who we've had that conversation
and how he fits into the Steelers
running back room and how you attack
that position group in the draft. Mike
McCarthy on the Steelers uh running back
who's heading into his sophomore season
with a lot of question marks. Quote, "I
am aware of their past experiences, but
this is like a Catholic operation. If
you say three Hail Marys, everybody has
a clean slate and let's get to work."
End quote.
>> Which I think is a great way to do it
from a new staff. I mean, obviously the
front office has a what what he put on
tape or didn't put on tape is still out
there. And you don't just throw away
what you think of the player just
because a new coaching staff comes in.
If you you question his pass blocking or
his cutting ability or whatever, I mean,
you still need to analyze the player as
impartially as possible without
question.
>> But you and I have been saying this for
a while. I mean, really since the
coaching hiring that I feel like Roman
Wilson and Caleb Johnson are not
necessarily the happiest, but sort of
the h career-wise the happiest of we can
get some new eyes on us. And I don't
think it was personal. We don't like
these two draft picks or whatever. Just
it didn't work out. They didn't live up
to expectations yet. They're still young
and they get a kind of a new lease on
life. And I'm glad McCarthy sees it that
way.
>> And I'm glad you bring up Roman Wilson
because McCarthy uh said that he
recently had a great conversation with
Roman Wilson saying new system, fresh
start. I'm hoping he's one of those guys
that would benefit from it. I was
impressed talking football with him.
There's a lot of people that have a lot
of love for him in the building.
>> Good. Good. I mean, I I they're
obviously going to continue to address
that position, but to what degree might
tell us a little bit about what they
feel his chances of not necessarily even
making the team, but being a real
contributor are. You mean do they
envision him of maybe he is a number
three? Like I definitely think they're
going to take one in the top two rounds
or very very early, but is there at
least a story they could tell that
Wilson might be our three? you know, is
he competing with a second round pick
and a fifth round pick and the two of
them are gonna
>> three and one's the four.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And battle it out or
situationally they'll be out there
differently. Who knows?
>> He was also uh obviously asked about how
they approach the quarterback position
in the draft. And he said, "I'm hopeful
there will be a quarterback, you know,
at the right time there for us to
probably add to our roster." Um,
>> that was one of the things that really
stood out to me.
>> And he said, "The other part of that is,
okay, what's the ceiling? What's the
floor?" or sometimes I get excited about
the floor. That kind of sounds like a
mid-round quarterback a little bit to
me, Matt Williamson.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I again, I have mixed
feelings if I think that's the right
move or not. And I really could make
equally strong cases if I was the
prosecuting or defending attorney in
terms of should they take a third to
fifth round quarterback. And obviously,
a lot of it has to do with who's
available and who it is. You don't just
take one to take one. But what stood out
to me, what you didn't mention there, he
said something along the lines of,
>> "I wish I had five quarterbacks in my
quarterback room every year. I wish the
NFL allowed that to happen." And it kind
of dawned on me that would be probably
good for the league to be honest with
you.
>> That's the development system that you
talk about.
>> Yeah. Right. Right. Maybe they could
make a, you know, every team gets four
quarterbacks no matter what, you know,
>> and then somebody break or salary
exemption or something.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. like that. I
mean, they just don't count against you
get 50 a 50man roster and four
quarterbacks, you know, something like
that or whatever. And would that be so
terrible have a guy hovering around for
a year or two just under Rogers and all
the stuff he would learn?
>> Yeah.
>> You know, I'm sure someone would cheat
and put Taesm Hill in there and then
then make him into a tight end or
something. But whatever, you know, they
can legislate that.
>> And the last thing,
>> he just wants to work with more and more
young guys at that position, which is
kind of his specialty, you know. And
then the last thing, Matt, we got about
I don't know two or three minutes here
till we got to go to break, but I I
wanted to make sure to mention this. He
talked about pos one thing that really
stood out to me. I put like two stars
next to this on my notepad here.
>> He talked about how position flexibility
is so critical for offensive line. Yeah.
>> How how often how often do you uh start
and finish the year with the same five
offensive linemen? It's rare. You got to
move those guys around. You got to make
it work on a week-toeek basis. M that
made my ears perk up because we've
talked a lot about the Steelers interest
in one of those offensive linemen that
has the potential to play guard and
tackle. Yes. You know, some of these
interior guys that can play all three
positions, guard, center, guard. I am uh
that made my ears perk up because I
think that's an even now that just
reinforces what we've talked about, a
real option for the Steelers at 21, at
53, you know, early in the draft. One of
those offensive linemen with versatility
and flexibility.
>> Yeah. And I don't want to look too much
into it, but the only offensive line
addition they made was Hoffman, right?
>> Yes.
>> And and he can play
>> he can play all three. Yeah. Right. It's
not just because he played with
McCarthy, you know, in Dallas. I think
that position flexibility is absolutely
important in that conversation.
>> Um like as much as I like Aone from Penn
State,
>> that's my only thing I don't love about
the situation is if you plug him in at
guard, you'd probably never move him
anyways
>> cuz he'd be so good
>> because yeah, he's a guard and he's
really good at it. So you wouldn't move
him anyways. but it doesn't influence
your left tackle problem at all or
potential upcoming problem
>> where some of these other guys, you
know, Proctor or
EH or whoever have Yeah. I mean, there's
a lot of those guys
>> have a more of a guard
>> than maybe tackle path. Yeah. And that
might be a tiebreaker for me, but
>> Maui Go is like that, too. Now, he's
going to be drafted way way out of the
Steelers range, but there's a lot of
guys that
>> there's a lot of guys fit that bold,
right? and and I like that better, you
know, but if he's a great guard and you
never have to move him, that's a pretty
good problem to have, too. Don't get me
wrong.
>> Um,
>> if he's Alan Fanica, you'll take it.
>> Yes.
>> Uh, one other thing that did stand out
to me, I know we're up against it, but
every time I've heard him speak in a
public setting, he's very appreciative
and knowledgeable of those who came
before him here. And obviously him and
Tomlin over overlapped as head coaches
and they had a relationship. But he even
brought up
>> chase each other in a Super Bowl.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean, he even brought up
Austin and going back to Cower and Null
and I mean, he and it's not just because
he's from Pittsburgh. I mean, I think I
mean, I'm sure that helps, but I mean, I
think he realizes what was built here
and I'm going to keep it going. I'm not
going to change the course of this
train. You know, we're not, you know,
laying new tracks, going the opposite
direction. you know,
>> as a guy who's been the steward of
>> probably the three biggest NFL
franchises in the Steelers, the Cowboys,
and the Packers, I think he gets I think
he gets how important that lineage and
that history is when you're with
organizations like that.
>> I got a kick out even when when Rogers
signed, he talked about how,
>> you know, obviously there was Jets in
between and he didn't mention them. He's
like, "Now I've been a part of two of of
the big, you know, like people know that
stuff, especially the older folks have
been around the league a long time and
appreciate it." Yeah, they sure do.
That's real. So, that's the kind of the
uh the Mike McCarthy hour here of the
drive to get us started today. We still
have two more hours to go. We're going
to have some fun guests for you. Uh
we're going to get into some more draft
conversation and there is certainly some
more national news. You know, we we kind
of focused on the Steelers for the first
hour there, but uh there were 15 other
AFC coaches who spoke today and and some
interesting stuff on that. Uh potential
update on Patrick Mahomes and his health
status recovering from that uh knee
injury. So, we've got plenty to get to
in the next two hours as we roll along
here at the Builtmore in Phoenix,
Arizona. It's our final day of league
meeting coverage. Wes Schuler, Matt
Williamson. It's the drive. Steelers
Nation radio on the Steelers Audio
Network.
Hour number two of the drive here on
this Tuesday inside the Builtmore in
Phoenix, Arizona. It is our final day of
on location shows here about 2,000 mi
from home for the NFL League meetings
2026 edition. And joining us now, a
familiar voice, a familiar name, of
course, the co-host of the Steelers
Blitz uh at noon on the Steelers Audio
Network with our guy Tom Opperman. It is
Chris Adansky. Also covers the Steelers
for the Trib. What's up, Buzz? How we
doing? You uh you enjoying this Arizona
sunshine?
>> It's a dry heat, I hear, right? It's a
dry heat here.
>> It makes sense, though. I finally get
it. Like Matt and I were talking about
this this morning.
>> The Uber driver today. Yeah.
>> 90° here doesn't feel like 90°.
>> Exactly. Right. Become a cliche and like
a joke, but it's actually true. Like you
come here, it was like 92 or something
yesterday. Right. It was warm,
>> but didn't feel like 92 in Pittsburgh is
a different 92.
>> Exactly. Right.
>> Our Uber driver was asking us where
we're from. You're from Pittsburgh. He's
like, "Yeah, I'm going up there in
August." And he was all worried about
it. He's like, "What's the
>> guy living here like it's super humid up
there,
>> right? Like what's the humidity like up
there?" I'm like, it's not like Georgia,
Florida, and you know what you hear
about the south. But yeah, it's I love
this weather out here. Now, I'm sure
it's much different in June and July and
August when it's 115 degrees outside.
>> But man, I can't imagine many places
with better weather in March than than
here in Arizona. Certainly, it's been
it's been a welcome development after
the winter that we had back home.
>> Chris Adamsky, uh, any difference in
your So, you were at the Mike McCarthy
breakfast this morning. Uh, you've been
boots on the ground here for about 24
hours now. Do you feel any differently
about Aaron Rogers uh today than you did
maybe 24 hours ago or before you got to
Arizona? Where where are you at in this
whole ongoing uh conversation?
>> I'd say it's more just a re
reaffirmation
uh more so. I I I probably felt that. I
was going to say I do yes probably feel
more confident that that Aaron Rogers
will be here or be with the here at some
point but I pro I probably felt that
yesterday you know two days ago too. So
I don't know how much it could have been
more rein but I guess reinforced I guess
is probably the the proper way to look
at it and
>> been a lot of communication it sounds
like.
>> Yeah. Yeah. He's I mean you wouldn't
think I know they have a you know human
relationship not a coach and they've
known each other for 20 years or
whatever but I don't think they'd be
talking to each other on the phone every
other day as as Mike McCarthy's
acknowledging over and over again that
they're they talked last night after the
after did all the meetings and
everything yesterday. So I don't think
you're
>> I think they did that last year or the
year before. Exactly. So I I there's
there's a obviously a purpose to a dup.
I don't think they're breaking down what
they're going to do on the second and
three and and you know in the first
quarter of a game, but I but I do think
there you know he said he's he's
involved. What was the word he used? Um
immersed in what's going on in the off
seasonason. He's keeping them so there's
definitely a degree of keeping things
communication there, keeping them posted
where they're at with everything. And uh
yeah, I I don't think it's ironclad. I
don't I don't think it's like a there's
a a thought outside that there's this um
submersive like oh he's definitely
coming we're not going to tell anybody.
I you know I don't think it's that I
don't think it's like okay keep this
quiet but but I do think there's a
general feeling that uh this is going to
happen here at some point.
>> Yeah and one thing Wes pointed out from
that interview too we just replayed it
last hour was he mentioned versatility
amongst his offensive linemen and we we
noted that Hoffman's the only guy that
they've added from outside the
organization. and he can play all three
interior spots. I certainly think
there's a really good chance maybe even
in round one that they invest in a
big-time prospect on the O line, someone
to play on the left side. But do you
think versatility is going to factor in
to that equation?
>> He talked a lot, you're right, you you
listen to about that his philosophy in
general both and and I think that's
generally just modern football anymore
and true certainly in in defense and all
but in defense the secondary. I mean,
we're going to talk a I'm sure you guys
are talking a lot about where's Jaylen
Ramsey go and all that. I just feel like
that'll be down to down uh game plan to
game plan week to week that type of
thing where you know there might be
games or situations where he's playing
but that that's just what in the
offensive lines part of that now it's
you know whether the Steelers kind of
had a you know say they weren't it
wasn't like we couldn't wait for Samo to
leave. It wasn't like kick him out the
door. Sometimes you get that point with
a veteran guy where no we're not
resigning him. I think there there was
interest or or they wanted to have him
back or open having him back.
>> Yeah. Um, so it it would be sort of
disingenuous to say, well, they expect
Spencer Anderson to just step in and
play right away whenever uh Sam say
could have been back and they obviously
bring in a a veteran free agent like
they have. But you're right, I you know,
if maybe a couple months ago, I maybe
just me my blind spot. I didn't think
offensive line was really a a a uh a big
possibility for the first round of the
draft. But the more and more this
process goes on, the more and more you
just hear more and more you kind of read
the tea leaves, the more you know, and
the Brick Jones thing. I think a couple
months ago, I don't think I was me
again, me didn't think would be a
physical question, a health question
mark at this point of the offseason as
we head into, you know, soon enough
here, good on the field. So, I think
that factors.
>> There was a little bit of news about I
wanted to follow up with you on that.
What are what are you hearing on Brick's
health?
>> Yeah,
I feel like
>> it's hard to get that information. Yeah,
it's
>> I I I don't I think medically wise I I
think there's the belief he's going to
be cleared to even by OTAAS and things
like like from a medical perspective,
but it's also like he he's an offensive
line. I mean, you need to you train your
body has been sort of, you know, neck
back type of thing here. We do your
offseason strength program, your
everything like that. It can't be done
really. So I think there is a little bit
of sort of like I don't think it's a
matter of he'll be out for the season or
anything like that but I think it's kind
of like okay where are we at with him
obviously then that isn't even I think
part of it if he was an allp pro left
tackle
>> then I was well okay he'll be fine by
but you know if he had his off
seasonason being like this and kind of
not be able to do so I think they kind
of have to approaching it they kind of
have to hedge things and we can't really
we'll see how it plays out and hopefully
he he is back hopefully you know builds
up and you know gets him physically
where he needs to be to be a starting
lineman and of Obviously then that's
it's kind of a separate issue, but it
all goes together the the performance
and where he's at and everything in
terms of what we've seen from him on
tape here the first three years of his
career. You had a good point though too.
I mean it's such a strength-based
position and I'm tr sure this is true to
some degree with almost every injury but
back and neck. I'm sure he's not
benching or doing rows or I mean
anything close to upper body. Maybe not
even lifting at all during this stretch.
I mean he has to lose some strength
during this whole process. Yeah, you're
right because isn't that obviously the
core in the back and there's so many I
mean I guess you could do legs I guess
and theoretically it wouldn't be but you
but just and you're talking about an NFL
offensive tackle. I mean that's
something that people kind of have
injuries. I get it but I just think all
the questions around it um in terms of
where he's at and physically and just
the neck in general type of thing. It it
it doesn't sound at all like it's
anything like not that they're different
players and I don't think anybody really
believed this but when you start getting
to the point where it's neck and things
like that last year there was a player
and I skipped my name right now that the
Texas defensive watch. Yes. Yes. And he
had to retire me. I don't they're not
anywhere to that level that degree or
anything but now it's just a point of
>> he can be physically cleared and then
it's like building building himself back
up. So it's still you know as we sit
here right now at this moment still
March just April's coming real soon
here. we're starting to build up toward
where it will does get too late um or it
gets late. It's still still early yet.
So, I think it can be okay. But, um
yeah, I don't I don't I think they're
happy with where medical wise in terms
of getting cleared that kind of thing. I
don't think there's anything a doctor
can say no, he can't do, you know.
>> You don't think they pick up his fifth
year option though, do you? I I really'd
be shocked.
>> Yeah, I'd be Yeah, I
>> mean, if he was a better player or 100%
healthy, but two strikes against you,
it's like
>> Yeah, it's really
>> And Cook's not bad, you know?
>> Exactly. of Cook and that and if we're
sitting here talking and I and I agree
with you that first round tackle is a
possibility, right? I mean,
>> not only if that h if that happens, it
even slams the door even more on on the
first on the fifth year option for for
Jones, but the fact that's even in play,
I mean, possibility. Yeah, it it says
kind of where things are at.
>> And it looks like there'll be guys to
pick from at 21 tackle. Some years you
can't even go down that road. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Chris Adamsky, co-host of the
Steelers Blitz, covers the Steelers for
the Trip with us here on our mini radio
row inside the Builtmore in Phoenix,
Arizona. Uh Chris,
>> we're doing a lot of heavy lifting on
radio row this year.
>> We are Texans have not held up their
side.
>> We are uh we're about onethird of the
radio representation down here.
>> Oh, I think we're about 90% of the radio
representation.
>> We're the uh we're the Aaron Rodgers in
this in this room down here. You know,
we're the ones walking right into Canton
one day and everyone else is just on the
coattails. Uh, speaking of quarterbacks
buzz, uh, there it continues to be a lot
of positive buzz from Mike McCarthy and
company on Will Howard. Uh, Mike
McCarthy saying that if he was in charge
of the draft last year, Will Howard
would not have lasted into the sixth
round? I I is this is this real? How
much of a crack is he going to get? Do
they really feel like at least maybe by
the time we get out of Latroe, he can be
the clear-cut number two?
>> Yeah, there's I I do believe that
there's genuine um curiosity. There's
genuine admiration from afar from the
from the coaching staff that came in.
Mike McCarthy remember he did talk he
took the he said he and he said that and
he talked about watching Will I mean
Will Howard I always talk about he was
the arguably he wasn't but the highest
he was the starting quarterback on the
national championship team. So he got
more airtime than any college football
player in the country two years ago. Um
so everybody kind of knew who he was and
and kind of followed him. So, and I
think there was that admiration seeing
how well he played during that that
stretch and whenever you're at the at
that point during that college football
playoff run by Will Howard last year
that just right when Mike McCarthy had
been let go or left or parted ways I
should say with the Cowboys everyone put
it so he he was watching more football
at that point than he had so he saw like
peak Will Howard tape at that he's
watching it live in terms of of what
what he's doing. So, I I do believe that
it's genuine for sure that that the that
the offensive staff and and Mike in
particular um like Will Howard, but but
I also don't there there's something to
say he's we like him better than a six
round pick to say he's going to have to
be a franchise quarterback, right? I
mean, so yeah, but so but I guess the
way Wes even talked about the other
frame of the question. Yes, I I do think
there's certainly a possibility that
there's a scenario where he he could be
the number two this as soon as this
year. But
>> there's also the possibility that, you
know, you add the veteran, assuming it's
Rogers, and then they draft a
quarterback in the, you know, in the mid
rounds or whatever, and you're not going
to cut him, then then all of a sudden, I
don't want to say he'll get cut, but all
of a sudden it gets a little hairy, you
know, where he's at at all in the depth
chart. Right. That's what I was going to
ask you next is because I've said this
eight million times that I understand a
case for and against a third, fourth,
fifth round quarterback. And some I like
better than others, some they'll like
better than others. They have to be the
right guy available. But that probably
is the writing on the wall for Rudolph
if you take him. I am always in favor of
taking a bite at the apple. You might
get a cheap, you know, home run Brock
party situation, Dak Prescott situation.
He wants to work with young
quarterbacks. Stephen said, "I wish I
had five in my room this year."
>> Do you think they do it? And would you
do it?
>> Yeah. I mean, I Well, Mark, there's
there's at least one other person who's
a bigger Will or Mason Rudolph fan
amongst the media than than I am, but I
I've been always proponent of of Mason
Rudolph, but uh
>> and that's not a knock on Rudolph. It's
just they're not going to keep four.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. Exactly. And and
>> he's only contract one more year.
>> And I totally agree with you. you laid
out the reasons why taking a mid-round
quarterback cuz that you go into the
process you think okay if if they fall
in love with Ty or if they still do I
shouldn't use the past if Tai Simpson if
they that's something you don't pass up
you don't worry about
>> that's a little different you don't
worry about if you you think you have a
franchise guy in the first round you're
taking the pick everything else is is
you know secondary you worry about that
later but if you start going into the
mid rounds there all of a sudden you
know no one that you one way or another
they'll have Rogers or if there's
somebody else but if there's Rogers and
then there's Um, yeah. And you have
these guys are going to make the team.
>> Yeah. And and so then you only three at
at the, you know, are going to make the
team. So you have to look at it. That's
that says something about somebody,
right? If you take in the mid- rounds,
you would think or at least it spells
>> trouble for some. It's Rudolph or right?
It's some because all four of them can't
make the team. Now
>> Rudolph might flip him into a six round
pick or something to a team that needs
him or team that gets injured, you know,
>> and and that's what what I think is it's
a little bit interesting is um
Just watching Ben Rothesber over the
final eight or nine years of his career
at training camp. He did the thing where
full practice, half practice, no
practice. And at least the first year
for Aaron Rogers, maybe because it was a
new team, maybe. I don't know. I was
surprised. I assumed at age 41 last
year, we wouldn't see him very much in
the trophy.
>> Only missed two practices the whole
year,
>> right? Yeah. He was out there reps to go
around for all these young guys.
>> So, part of me thinks like they'll roll
the ball out there and and you know, do
the oldfashioned like, okay, Will, you
know, show us not you know, you deserve
to be part of the future. Okay, Mason,
show us you deserve to be part of this
team. And if you threw me in there, it
makes it all of a sudden there's not
that many reps to go around.
>> Exactly. So it's a little bit harder.
Yeah. If you're trying to get your
starter prepared for the season. So that
isn't ideal. But I mean I do Especially
when you have 12 draft picks, Matt. You
your your idea would take a bite at the
apple. Yeah. It's a lot more tenable.
You almost I don't want to say you have
to
>> then you have to have a plan in place.
How do I get these guys developed?
>> But it's like it's almost harder to take
12 picks and not take a quarterback,
right? Is for the situation. So, it's
almost like you kind of you'd almost be
waiting because you you take 12 picks at
other positions and that's another it's
hard for those 12 guys to make the team
as it is. Now, you throw an extra guy in
there at a position that it's going to
be hard to make the team
>> that you want need to spend time
developing. It's a fourth round
quarterback. He's going to make the
team.
>> Yes. Couple more minutes here with our
buddy Chris Adamsky. Uh Chris, I wanted
to ask you just, you know, maybe kind of
a a national thing or two as it relates
to these uh these league meetings here.
What's your I guess on a scale of calm,
concerned, worried, and panicked. Okay.
Where are you at on the uh on the NFL
referees association and this stalemate
with the league?
>> Um I I mean I'm generally calmed to
concerned. I I guess I don't know. I
It's get up a lot brought up now a lot
the uh the fail Mary and things. I get
maybe after that selective memory where
it wasn't so I'm like a little you know
it'll work it there's labor dispute will
work itself out even if they start the
season play a few weeks then you know
then the negotiation will come together
but I guess you're right that if a
high-profile um mistake is made of some
that that's what ended the uh the
dispute last time what 13 years ago 14
years ago now when that happened is a
high high-profile gaff so you hope that
you know if you're the Steelers you're
not the one that happens to maybe you'll
benefit from it though like oh this is
actually the best
>> this is Um but you know and again just
like I said there's lots of time we talk
about broader challenge we're still it's
still march as we see here today there's
not a a game of consequence for four and
a half months or over four month or five
months I should say and even exhibition
games aren't for over four months. So I
think there's still plenty of time and
you know these negotiations it's things
that you know there's a little rhetoric
going out the last couple days but
that's just part of the part of the
process
>> trying to win the narrative. Right.
>> Exactly. So I I I think that if if we're
still here and it's August August 1st
instead of uh you know April 1st about
to hear then maybe the the level rises
but I think it'll be all right.
>> Last thing I have for you and I I think
we all agree
Roman Wilson, Caleb Johnson haven't
lived up to their draft expectations
obviously, but just listening to
McCarthy and it's something I've kind of
inferred to this point. They're going to
get somewhat of a new lease on life,
don't you think?
>> Yeah. I mean, those two are probably the
two of the that I don't say happy about
the coaching change, but the
>> that's the same words I use. I mean, at
least it's new eyeballs when you're
right. I mean, it's there's a clean
slate aspect anytime there's a a new
coach that comes and whatever you know
the and and the the staff that drafted
and I mean the coaching staff and I know
they hit Mike Tom with influence
obviously, but they're still on hand
here. There was things that they the
Steelers liked about those two players.
They took them in the third round. So,
you still have that kind of support
behind you and you have a new set of
eyes. Now, just by so far what they've
done, the Steelers um free agency wise
and there's a long way to go with the
draft and everything and that could flip
on its head, but they haven't been as I
mean Michael Pitman's that's aggressive
and it was the first moments of free
agency essentially, but aside from that,
the res been kind of quiet at wide
receiver and when you go out and
obviously more receivers play, more
receivers are part of your game day
roster, blah blah blah. Um, so but as we
stand right now, Rowan Wilson is
probably still, you know, a starting re
as as the depth drawact.
I don't expect that to be the case, but
I think that is a little bit of an
indication that he's maybe in higher st
because it's going to be
>> Caleb better whether he figures out the
kickoff return thing, gets back in good
graces with that, or whether he figures
out another role on special teams
because right now the number three
running back,
>> you got to play teams. You have to play
teams.
>> So if he doesn't do that, that's when it
start. Now, he's still only a second
year. It's a lot more feasible to to
move on from somebody into in a third
year when you're a third round pick than
a second year. It's pretty rare. I don't
know. But how often does a third round
pick cut before his second season
starts?
>> Not very. But he was also drafted for a
different system. And maybe there's a
team out there that had a really high
grade on him one year ago. And I mean,
you wouldn't get close to your
investment. You might get a six round
pick back or return. But
>> and I still think again, if we have 12
picks, they might draft a running back
still. I mean, even with the homers.
>> Oh, you're definitely right.
>> You know, and then all of a sudden it
gets real tight.
>> Yeah, you're right. That's an excellent
point. That's an excellent point. And
just again, it's a teles hate to read
too much into we all hang on everywhere
at this point, but
>> both with um the general manager and the
coach McCarthy and and Omar so far. If I
feel like the answers are more
enthusiastic about a Roman Wilson than
they are about Caleb GR.
>> Yeah, I I got those vibes, too. Plus,
there's more roster spots to go around.
Yes. You know, right.
>> Yeah. So there's a lot there's a lot of
reasons why Roman seems a little in a
better spot right now.
>> Yes.
>> Then Roman does have to run down on
kickoffs to save his job.
>> Exactly.
>> We are in a better spot after having
about 18 minutes with our friend Chris
Adamsky. Make sure you're checking out
all his work in the trim this week and
of course listening to him and Tom here
on the Steelers Blitz on the Steelers
Audio Network. Buzz, thanks for the
time. Go Mars Planets.
>> There you go. MS Mars Mars. We'll be
back with some uh around the league
conversation, other news of the day when
we return. Weser, Matt Williamson here
inside the Builtmore in Phoenix,
Arizona. All part of our ongoing
coverage of the league meetings on
Steelers Nation Radio on the Steelers
Audio Network.
Back on the drive here inside the
Builtmore. It is our final day of annual
league meeting coverage. the 2026
edition here in Phoenix, Arizona.
>> It's been good so far, huh,
>> Matt? Great.
>> You I was I was joking with you when we
were walking over here this morning
after getting our uh highly valuable
swag bags.
>> Yeah, I'm excited to dig in. What's all
in these bags that uh I think we started
a little bit of a firestorm cuz after us
there was about a dozen members of the
Steelers.
>> We were smart. Kept kept our mouth
quiet, one of the first ones in and then
we start spreading the word. Right.
>> Exactly. Right. That's exactly get your
goodies.
>> Take care of yourself first, right? And
then you
>> Yeah. Yeah. You know, that's the golden
rule, I think, right? Is take care of
yourself and then worry about others.
And that's exactly what we did this
morning. I was telling you when we were
walking back over here, I was like,
Matt, you told me how awesome these few
days were and how cool all this was.
>> Yeah. It's just a different world.
>> But I think you even undersold it a
little bit. I mean, it was undersold and
overd delivered. I mean, the uh the just
the access, the property here, the the
meals, the food. The one thing we might
have to do before we even like sneak
over before we Uber back to the hotel is
>> see how far we can get back into the the
really really nice area of the hotel.
>> Kind of get me in trouble. Huh.
>> Well, we're not going to like break down
any barriers or anything, but we'll just
see how far we can meander back there
because I think the deeper and deeper
you get into the property, it's like
villas and, you know, super expensive
stuff. You know,
>> Matt's a little bit braver than me in
these uh in these.
>> Next year you will be in these settings.
He likes to uh he likes to push the
boundaries of the credential and see how
far it can get us.
>> Pretend like you belong.
>> That's half the battle. That's half the
battle, right? And uh and that that
certainly was half the battle of us
getting this big Nike bag into a bag.
>> It's like walking into a beer
distributor when you're 17. You got to
look like you belong.
>> I wouldn't know anything about that. I
don't know. I don't know what you're
talking about. Uh Matt, obviously we a
lot of Steelers moving and shaking
through the first about halfway home.
>> Yeah. A lot lot of I wouldn't say news,
but a lot of moving and shaking. That's
a good way of putting it, right?
>> Things that obviously deser deserve
conversation, but with the AFC head
coaches breakfast today, 15 other head
coaches uh spoke. There's been some more
GMs and owners uh that have, you know,
spoke in the last uh what, you know, 21
hours or so since we were last on air
yesterday. I think a big piece of news,
at least something that struck me this
morning is um it seems like there's a
lot of confidence amongst the Kansas
City Chiefs that Patrick Mahomes is
going to be ready for the opener.
>> Oh wow. I haven't seen any of this news
yet. We've been on the air. Yeah. Right.
>> And and you know um Andy Reid seemed
optimistic when he was asked about that
at his uh you know media availability
this morning. And then Adam Sheffer
actually not too far from from where we
sit here out in front of the facility
went on the Pat McAfee show and said
give Patrick Mahomes five more months
and he's going to be ready for the
opener. That's what I expect. I think he
will be back.
>> So Medicine's come a long way. You know
I mean there's no doubt about that.
>> Injuries have come a long way.
>> He's played through one of the most
underrated things about Mahomes is some
of the stuff he's played through too. I
mean, he's he's had some of these
catastrophic looking ankle injuries in
the wild card round or whatever and
still takes his team to the Super Bowl.
And there are some people like that and
knock on wood like Cam Hayward always
talks about how he has like Wolverine
blood and he just heals quicker than
others. And I think some of it extreme
athletes and guys that are bodies are
even
better than those that are I mean
everyone that plays in the league is the
top 1% of humans walking the planet but
there's even the 1% of those guys that
are a little more athletic, a little
more limber, a little stronger, a little
more balanced, etc. And there's nobody
epitomizes that more than Mahomes. Plus
the other thing people just think he
gets by on ability. his work ethic is
through the roof and he's gonna train to
no end.
>> But still, when they traded for Justin
Fields, I thought, uh, maybe though
it'll be week three until he comes back.
You know, Fields will play the whole
preseason, which I'm sure he'll do no
matter what, and Andy Reid will try to
revitalize a really talented player kind
of at a crossroads in his career, Fields
obviously.
>> And maybe they'll just run the ball like
crazy for the uh first two weeks of the
season or something like that.
you got the Super Bowl
>> MVP.
>> And you signed a, you know, a running
back for that reason, I assume.
>> Um, but I'd rather run with Mahomes.
>> Yeah.
>> You know,
>> I'd rather have a healthy Mahomes. That
is for sure. So, that one that one was
interesting to me because it seemed
seemed like a lot of confidence that
he'll be ready to go in in September uh
when the season gets rolling.
>> And the league's better for it.
>> Absolutely.
>> I mean, it's one of the best
quarterbacks that's ever lived. you
know, they don't want him on the
sidelines.
>> And I think there is a you can draw a
direct correlation in this league to the
quality of the product and the quality
of the quarterback play.
>> They don't want Josh Allen and Lamar and
these Burrow and these guys missing
time.
>> Exactly. Right.
>> And Lamar and Burrow missed too much
time.
>> Exactly right. Uh and speaking let's
let's stay there, Matt. Um in
quarterback conversations, uh some
interesting stuff today in regards to uh
what the Cleveland Browns are going to
do in the AFC North at the quarterback
position. Uh uh so Jimmy Hasslam,
Brown's owner, spoke uh as did uh
obviously their uh new head coach Todd
Monkin. And I don't know if I want to
say that it's a disconnect, but
basically Jimmy Hasslam said he told
reporters that Deshun Watson has a quote
great chance to be Cleveland's starting
quarterback.
>> Okay.
>> And then Monin kind of followed that up
this morning saying the reps won't be
evenly divided in this quarterback
battle. It will be based on what we've
seen in the past and where we ended last
year in terms of how this is all going
to go about with of course Shador
Sanders, Deshun Watson, and Dylan
Gabriel.
>> So Jimmy Hasslam was not the owner of
the Browns when I was there. Um that's
how long ago I was there. But my hunch
is when the owner says he's going to be
in the mix, he's going to be in the mix.
I mean, are we going to listen to the
head coach who didn't say he's not going
to be in the mix to be fair, or are we
going to listen to his boss who says he
is going to be in the mix and remembers
the ridiculous investment they made in
Watson? What I find kind of funny is the
dude they drafted in the third round,
Dylan Gabriel's name like never even
comes up anymore, you know, like
>> ever. And he started what, like the
first 10 games of the season,
>> right? Yeah. They drafted him two rounds
ahead of Shadore and there were some
weird things going on there. Don't get
me wrong. It's not a a normal draft
progression, but I do think it's going
to be like a Shadore Watson
um competition in camp. And could some
team grab Gabriel for sixth round pick?
I mean, I always thought he's a solid
backup, you know, potentially. Um I my
hunch is, and this probably goes without
saying, is they don't have their
quarterback and I don't think they'll
pursue it until next year. Sure. and
they have a chance to build a decent
nest with all these picks and they are a
free spending team.
>> That's got to be job number one for this
new staff and new regime is let's build
let's build the nest so that when we do
find the quarterback we're you know we
put them in the best situation.
>> Receivers and O linemen are going to be
stressed heavily in this draft for them.
Um
off the- field stuff aside about Watson
though, I mean I'm not saying that's
water in the bridge or it doesn't
matter. I'd love to see him play right
now.
>> Just in terms of the curiosity aspect.
>> Yeah, total curiosity. I mean, the day
they traded for him, I thought he was a
top five quarterback.
>> He was without a doubt.
>> I mean, he was a phenomenal player. And
trust me, I'm not rooting for him. I
mean, there's probably no in the league
I'm rooting for less, to be very honest
with you, considering the team he plays
for and his background and all that
stuff, too. But,
>> I'm extremely curious. Is he going to be
the worst quarterback in the league? Is
could he get back to being good? Could
he be the 14th best quarterback,
>> right? I mean, how much work has he put
in? Does he look like he hasn't touched
the football in two years? I mean, I
just think it's a fascinating study, you
know, a scientific experiment.
>> So, he had that unbelievable 2020 season
with Houston. Yeah.
>> Um where they probably should have
beaten the Chiefs in the PA in the
playoffs, but had that just crazy game.
He led the league in passing uh that
year. He led the league in yards per
completion that year, yards per attempt
that year. 33 touchdowns to only seven
interceptions. Uh as well as mobility as
well as Exactly. Right. Um
>> and then 21 sits out. And since then,
Matt sat out in 21, sat out in 25. So
he's played he's played 22, 23, 24.
>> Were they all Browns
>> for the Browns? Yes.
>> Played six games in 22, six games in 23,
seven games in 24.
>> And he was like the worst quarterback in
the league for all of them.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. I'm like, "This totally fell off a
cliff."
>> And so I
>> and he's got all his guaranteed money
and we know the off-field stuff and you
know
>> I would be shocked if he can get back to
even a league average quarterback but he
just turned 31 years old which for a
quarterback is right in the middle of
your prime.
>> Yeah. And
at least you know if you're looking at
the Browns maybe they think they have
something at Chador and maybe they do.
Who knows? But if you're playing Watson
like I said they're going to divvy up
the snaps. Let's say they give them 40%
of the action when OTAAS and mini camps
roll around and then go from there. It's
not like you're restricting,
you know, some super high investment
pick, you know, it's not like Cam Ward,
we're not letting you get out there and
let you develop, you know, I mean, the
guys that he would be stealing reps off
of aren't the first overall pick or
they're not meant to even first round
picks.
>> Yeah. Right. It's not like, "Hey, we
just drafted Mendoza. Now we're going to
play him that much." Simpson. Yeah.
Somebody's in the way like Watson. Like,
no.
>> Hey, it will be It always is interesting
to see how things play out in Cleveland,
but I think it certainly will be,
particularly from that quarterback
perspective here as the offseason
programs begin.
>> It'll at least be interesting.
>> Absolutely.
>> Right. Right. Absolutely. I'm not
>> Not interesting. Not interesting because
it's going to be pretty, but
>> No, it probably won't go well.
>> Probably won't go well.
>> No, I'm I'm certain it won't. But
>> Matt, uh, Dan Campbell saying, uh, today
that he's considering switching allp pro
right tackle pane SU to left tackle for
the 2026 season. Yeah.
>> Depending on how the rest of the
offseason shakes out.
>> So, I find this interesting, too. Like,
originally, I'd heard this was mentioned
like a month or so ago. I'm like, him or
Lane Johnson's the best right tackle on
the planet. Why would you ever mess with
something that's almost as close to
perfect as football gets? But their O
line's in a bit of a disarray and they
don't pick too far away from the
Steelers. They're going to be looking at
a lot of the similar O line prospects,
Proctor and Fo and Layu and all those
dudes. And I think they want the the
versatility on draft day to say we don't
have to take a left or we don't have to
take a right. And I gave it some thought
too. I mean, Soul, like Tristan Worfs,
>> is in the top 1% of all the offensive
tackles in terms of ability.
Unbelievable. I mean, it So, Andy was a
left tackle in Oregon. As successful as
he's been at right tackle,
>> I mentioned Worfs because the Bucks did
the exact same thing with Worfs, too, is
they
>> drafted a left tackle, made him a right
tackle, he was basically the best in the
league, and then switched him back a
year or two ago,
>> and he's one of the best
>> and it didn't matter at all because he's
so good.
>> He's unbelievable. So maybe Su would
just be like, I'm that good. It doesn't
matter.
>> You know, and he might be, you know,
like we've talked about for years.
>> It's like, you know, it works both ways.
Sometimes they start those guys on the
right. They're great, and they leave
them there. Like like Lane Johnson. I
think a lot of people thought eventually
Lane Johnson would move to the left side
for the Eagles, but he just stayed
there.
>> Um, so there's no right or wrong answer.
>> Yeah. And there's more flip-flopping
than there used to be. Used to be
>> right tackles are the brawlers and the
left tackles are the dancing bears. and
you don't flip them. And there's a lot
of famous quotes about, you know, it's
like wiping yourself with the other hand
if you flip and all those things. But
like look at Falanu's uh draft class.
There was like six tackles drafted in
the first half of round one.
>> Switched.
>> They're all over the place. You know,
Alt goes from left to right. He's still
great. Falanu was a left tackle. He goes
to right. He's great. You know, maybe
it's easier now. I'm just open to that.
>> Yeah. No, I I I I certainly think that
is definitely something that has evolved
and you got to kind of change your
process with that uh as opposed to how
we all felt 10 years ago.
>> Like Penny Soul was sitting here be
like, I don't care. I'll be fine.
>> I'll be fine. I'll be great. I'll be
great. They're not going to pay me big
money. I'll be great on either side. I
don't care.
>> No one's going to get bash me, right?
>> Whatever's whatever's best for the team.
>> Uh Chris Ballard, another name that you
and I have discussed a little bit
throughout the offseason, Matt, is uh
Colts quarterback Anthony Richardson.
and
>> yeah,
>> how of all the different I guess if you
want to label him potential reclamation
projects, he would probably
>> everyone wants the Baker, the Daniel
Jones, the Darnold. Right. Right. Right.
>> Um and so we've kind of uh mentioned
that he would be the guy that we'd be
most interested in that regard. Uh and
that it seems like the Colts are ready
to move on. But Chris Ballard saying
today there is a scenario where
Richardson stays with the Colts. Uh
quote, "There's definitely a scenario
there. He's a good dude. He's talented.
I still want good for Anthony. I think
he's still got a lot in him. He's had
some freaking bad luck, but I still
think Anony's got a lot of ability and
he's maturing and growing and he's still
young. Anytime you take a quarterback
that high, the expectations, it's hard
to live up to them no matter who you
are.
>> Yeah, I've never thought he's somebody
they have to trade. Got to get this guy
out of the out of the room. I mean, no
one's ever said,
>> especially with Daniel Jones and he be
ready for the start of the season, too.
Like, he might need Richardson. I I know
they have Riley Leonard, but I think
he's nowhere near the prospect
Richardson was or the ceiling Richardson
was. And Jones probably I know Jones
won't be available for OTAA's mini camp,
probably well into training camp, maybe
not even the beginning of the season. If
you're the Colts, wouldn't you at least
want to instead of dumping him for a
fifth round pick, wouldn't you at least
want to
>> give three or four months worth more of
him actually playing football? I mean,
he had a broken orbital bone, but he's
going to be fine now. I mean, that's
that's not a a lingering injury or, you
know, an athletic changing injury. He's
still going to run. He's still going to
throw you blah blah blah. So, if
somebody comes and knocks your doors
off, great. But there's a lot of these
quarterbacks I thought would definitely
be on the move, like the M. Jones of the
world that just haven't been. And there
hasn't been quite as much quarterback
movement around the league. Everyone's
kind of settled even if you don't
include the Steelers, you know, and
where would it even go?
>> It's a good point. You know, especially
if you take the Steelers out of the
conversation,
>> right? Which I think it's going to be
Rogers and the two guys and maybe a pick
and that's pretty much written on the
wall.
>> There's so you keep them.
>> There's some of the other moving and
shaking of the day. We have a few more
tees to cross and eyes to dot when we
wrap up hour number two on the other
side. Our buddy Alan Saunders from
Steelers Now is going to join us in the
bonus hour, third hour before we get out
of here. We'll also get to uh to plenty
of your tweets as we roll along here
inside the Builtmore. We are on location
in Arizona for the annual league
meetings. Wesler, Matt Williamson. It is
the drive. Steelers Nation radio on the
Steelers Audio Network.
Closing down the second hour of the show
here on our third day at the league
meetings. It is the drive on location
about 2,000 miles away from our studios
in Bridgeville, Pennsylvania, here in
Phoenix, Arizona, where it's sunny,
where it's beautiful, all the moving and
shaking of the annual league meetings.
And Matt, across the timeline here, via
Tom Pelisero, of course, of the NFL
Network, uh the NFL owners have approved
four rule changes.
>> Okay,
>> so here's here's what they are. These
things happen while we're here, too.
Yeah. Right. There's a reason everybody
gets together.
>> I thought it was for the fancy dinner
last night.
>> Right. Right.
>> Steak and the sushi and the smoked
watermelon margarita
>> and the Mexican floating around down
here and all that good stuff, too.
>> I'm about to I'm about to I'm about to
just abuse a burrito later for dinner. I
can't wait.
>> I think that's a good move.
>> Tom Pelisero saying, "These four have
passed. The first um to permit the
kicking team to declare an onside kick
at any time during the game has passed."
>> Boom. I mean, I thought that was an easy
one. And I still 97% of them will still
be in the fourth quarter. Of course,
>> 98% of them will still be in the fourth
quarter.
>> But if someone's shooting the four first
doesn't make it smart, but do it. Who
cares, right?
>> If you're down 17 points at the end of
the third quarter,
>> yeah, go for it.
>> Desperate times, you know. Right. Right.
Right.
>> Desperate times, desperate measures, all
that good stuff. Yeah, that
>> I think they just screwed that up when
they wrote it the first time.
>> Same.
>> You know, let's just correct it a year
or two later.
>> And that's how a lot of these things
work.
>> Exactly. Exactly.
>> That's why you have competition
committees, right? Uh, the second thing
that has passed here in Arizona is
eliminating the kicking team's incentive
to intentionally kick the ball out of
bounds when kicking off from the 50 yard
line.
>> That was a total loophole.
>> That was one of
>> I just think they just didn't think
through.
>> Yep. Special teams, how could you? Yeah,
it was the first time going through it.
>> Um, and so yeah, we saw that. Danny
Smith did that a couple times last year.
Uh, we saw it I remember in Dublin was
one of the times.
>> Yeah. Yeah. um
>> drill it out of bounds and
>> drill out of bounds and you end up
getting five yard you give the offense
five yards less of uh you know of field
of field position in the process too.
>> Kind of a helpless feeling if you're the
return team.
>> Yes. So that one uh certainly a little
bit of a loophole. Uh
>> so how did they word it? You're not
allowed to drill it out of bounds.
>> Yes. Now so again I think they did by
accident.
>> They probably still have to decide the
parameters on that. Maybe
>> I guess there's a big penalty. Maybe
it's a big penalty or it's just if you
kick it out of bounds, the ball goes
here.
>> You know, it's just it's just,
you know, it's at the 35 or it's
probably what it is, right?
>> Or whatever. So, some of the language of
these rules will still have to be
>> um delegated,
but but we know at least that
>> but what was proposed passed.
>> Yes. To eliminate that incentive to
intentionally kick the ball out of
bounds has passed. So, that's two of the
four. And um a third one also directly
we we talked about this on Sunday on our
kind of opening uh show and our our kind
of primer and 411 to set the scene here
for for the week. Um a lot of this
related
>> 411 mean
>> 411 is like need it's like your
information like 411.
>> Well I know but like what's why did that
come about?
>> That's a good question.
>> Why isn't it 287?
>> It's 411 relevant information or the
truth. What does the slang term 411
mean? Where did it derive from? I guess
is my
>> originates from the United States
telephone system where 411 was the
number dialed for directory assistance
to get information.
>> So it's like 911, you know, like there's
certain numbers you punched.
>> It was Google basically before Google.
You dial 411, you could get your
information. Uh so give me the 411 is
all the news, all the all the gossip,
all the lowdown
>> way before internet and what
>> on a on a particular subject.
>> Yeah, I understood what it meant. I just
didn't know where it came from.
>> Hey, we're learning something new here
every day. A lot of these, as we shared
with you, are related to the kickoffs.
And the third rule change that has
passed is also related to kickoff to
modify the kickoff alignment
requirements for the receiving team
players in the setup zone.
>> So, they're allowing that.
>> They're allowing that. So, teams will
have a little more wiggle room, a little
more freedom to how they want to uh
align on kickoffs. Now, it's not rigid
and set and stacked. It has to be this
way.
>> Again, that's both we both leaned that
way whenever we brought this stuff up,
you know, when we got here. And again, I
mean, like, if you're going to allow
defense coordinators, offense
coordinators, play designers on those
sides of the ball to be more creative
with their formations and schemes, why
not let the special team coaches do it,
too?
>> It makes a ton of sense.
>> Yeah. Yeah,
>> absolutely. Makes a ton of sense. So,
those three, I think we thought that
there was a really good chance that
those three would pass. All related to
>> I bet there wasn't much resistance on
those.
>> All related to the kickoff, all of those
proposed by the competition committee.
Uh, and according to Tom Pelisero,
>> you need to remember the whole dynamic
kickoff still pretty new.
>> It's we're only going into year three
here. So, we're the dynamic kickoff is
still on its rookie deal entering
>> still rookie deal right now.
>> Looks like they'll pick up a fifth year
auction, right?
>> I don't think it's going anywhere. I
don't think they'll have to think about
that one too much. And then finally,
Matt, the fourth and final rule change
uh that has passed according to Tom
Pelisero of the NFL Network is that
for one year only, the NFL will allow
the officiating department to correct
clear and obvious misses made by onfield
officials that impact the game in the
event that there is a work stoppage
involving the game officials uh
represented by the NFL referees
association.
>> Yeah. And at a minimum, this ref thing
is not going to go away soon. I'm sure
we'll be talking about this for weeks,
maybe months, hopefully not months and
months and months. Um, my takeaway, and
this really reaffirms it, is at a
minimum, the owners in the league are
putting pressure on the refs.
>> Yes. And that's all it is. Maybe it's
all 101. Right. Right. Right.
>> But that's at least that much.
>> Yes.
>> I mean, they're they're they're push
pushing the hammer down a little bit.
Oh, and also uh via Pelisero, NFL owners
also just approved an amended rule
change that not only will allow league
personnel to consult with onfield
officials when considering
disqualifications. Remember we talked
about this?
>> Yeah. Like spitting incidents and things
like that,
>> spitting and punching and stamping.
>> Um so not only uh to review those type
of things uh but also to uh throw a flag
on the play as well too. So not only
>> that did get approved.
>> Yes. Okay. So, not only could someone
from the league office or from the
booth, you know, buzz down and say,
"Hey, uh, Jamar Chase just spit on
Jaylen Ramsay. You got you got to eject
him out." You could also say you could
throw a 15 yard personal foul on that
even if the referees miss at all.
>> Good. Um, again, I think I brought this
up two days ago that
>> that should happen. I don't want people
getting away with disgusting acts and
things like that.
>> Yeah, I agree.
>> But how far do we take it? You know, is
it like
>> a shove?
>> Yeah. Right. Right. Right. Oh, he might
have hit him in the face mask after the
penalty.
>> Slight little palm to the face or does
it have to be a groin punch? Does it
have to be a stomp on the ankle? Does it
have to be putting your hand around
somebody's throat? You know, like
>> that does leave some interpretation up
to the officials.
>> I'm not super worried about it, but I
don't want someone to take it too far.
Like, we're going to review that. Come
on. You know,
>> that's where I'm with you. I obviously I
want technology to be part of the game,
>> but I don't want it to take over the
game.
>> Yes.
>> I think that's the balance. kind of like
in the Chase situation, it would have
absolutely changed the game, you know,
right?
>> I said this to you a few days ago. I I
think there there's not a lot that uh
that sports fans across the board all
agree upon, but I don't care if it's
football, baseball, basketball, hockey.
I think everybody wants technology to be
a part of the game. Yeah. They just
don't want it to take over and and clunk
up the the flow of the game at the same
time. There's a balance there that we're
all looking to strike.
>> Yes,
>> Matt. Couple more uh teased to cross and
eyes to dot before we put a bow here on
hour number two. The Super Bowl is
officially returning to Las Vegas in
2029.
>> Okay.
>> Oh boy, that'll be that'll be a fun
scene. Think many people want to go.
>> I think that'll be a fun scene there in
Las Vegas. Also, don't tell anybody I
told you this. All right. But I was
listening to some little birdies chirp
last night at the uh at the dinner.
>> Yeah.
>> Sounds like Nashville in 2030, which oh
boy,
>> that wouldn't be a bad spot either.
>> That would not be a bad spot. But my
goodness, downtown Nashville is like
smaller than downtown Pittsburgh. And
>> wow,
>> that would be a lot of fun, but a lot of
chaos. Uh but we
>> the Steelers are there back to back. You
and I have a good time in Vegas and
Nashville.
>> Yes, exactly. We We sure will. We'll be
Listen, when we're uh when we're on the
NFL's diamond travel schedule, it won't
be a problem. We'll be we'll be we'll be
doing fantastic.
>> Uh also announced by the Minnesota
Vikings, they are picking up the
fifthear option on wide receiver Jordan
Addison.
>> I thought that was semi-debatable. You
know, like Naylor was up for free
agency. I thought they might try to just
keep him and let Addison go. Um,
Addison's a good player. He's a really
good number two, but he's very small.
And I think he's a slightly overrated
player that benefits so much from
Jefferson being on the other side.
>> And he keeps getting in trouble. I mean,
he just keeps getting in trouble over
and over and over. Now, fifth year
option for a guy like him, he's probably
not going to a Pro Bowl. Isn't really
real dis display dis display dis. Yeah.
Yeah.
>> And I do think the Vikings are in it to
win it this year with Kyler. I mean, I
don't think they're taking a step back
and trying to rebuild or anything, but I
didn't know if this was a slam dunk.
>> Yeah, I didn't either. I mean,
>> he's always in trouble.
>> That's that's the kicker. He's a good
number two, and you know, you used a
first round pick on him a few years ago.
>> Um, but
>> but the fifth year option is also
different than I'm going to give you a
huge contract with a $25 million
signing.
>> And as you mentioned, especially if he
he was he was a later first round pick
if he hasn't hit a lot of those in
>> I don't think he's hit a lot of the
kickers. Yeah,
>> the number probably isn't crazy. It's
probably a fair number to pay a number
two wide receiver.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> And maybe you end up if it if he walks
if he walks the line like Johnny Cash,
maybe you end up extending him. If not,
hey,
>> if he leaves at the end of the year, you
probably get a comp pick out of it, you
know.
>> Yeah. Exact. That's a good point, too.
Uh let's see here. Matt Dolphins GM,
John Eric Sullivan, shut down uh any
potential conversation regarding trade
rumors for Devon Achain earlier this
morning. Uh saying
>> I keep hearing that, but I don't know if
I believe it. is saying that it's a
priority for them to extend him and
there's zero effort to move him.
>> Okay. I mean, originally when he said
that a couple weeks ago, right after the
Waddle trade, I just thought, man, no
one's offered enough yet. His style, I
mean, running backs just don't last in
this league, especially tiny ones. By
the time you're good, is is that a good
investment?
>> I don't know. I don't think
>> I mean, he certainly helps with
evaluating Willis, which is super
important. That part is important,
right? I mean, swing passes to him and,
you know, sort of competitive.
>> You got to have somebody that can do
something for you on that offense.
>> And they'll probably draft two good pass
catcher or young pass catchers, you
know, pretty high. But still,
>> I would think that's a piece you want to
move.
>> Then one of the last things that uh that
I think we need to discuss here, Matt,
because it's not a huge story now, but I
think in the coming years it will be,
and that is that the NFL announced a
partnership with Tomorrow Sports, the
company behind, you know, that uh Total
Golf League that we've seen on ESPN
sometimes. It's all the pro golfers that
are in the indoor facility and they play
virtual golf.
>> The greens all change.
>> Yes. Rory Mroy does it. Tiger Woods does
it. Like they've got big names.
>> We were in Indianapolis was the first
time I ever saw it. Right.
>> It's the same company that does that. Uh
they are developing a professional flag
football league for both men and women
that will be backed by all 32 NFL teams.
So the NFL partnering with Tomorrow
Sports for a pro flag football league.
Matt, the reason why I think right now
this doesn't grab a bunch of headlines
or move the needle, but it will
eventually is because remember a little
over two years from now, summer of 2028,
the summer Olympics are in Los Angeles
here in the United States and flag
football is going to be for the first
time an Olympic sport. So this, I think,
is the ramp up to that of
>> people used to have get people used to
it, get people interested in it, get NFL
players involved to see exactly what
that looks like because they are vastly
different games that are governed
differently and played differently. But
that I just think is important. I think
that's something that again today isn't
going to grab a bunch of headlines, but
I think this is the start of potentially
something that could be substantial in
in a couple years.
>> Yeah. And there was a a get together
here where um Larry was involved. Larry
Fitzgerald was involved.
>> That's right. We ran into your old
buddy. That's one of the things in all
the fun of yesterday. We forgot to bring
>> It was yesterday, right? It was about
two days ago. Everything kind of blended
together. But yeah, he was here
promoting that with some other people
and I guess it went well. I didn't sit
in there, but I did run into Larry
before. We we you know,
>> I thought I thought you would maybe
talk, you know, I'd heard from you for a
long time how good how good buddies you
are with Larry Fitzgerald and all this.
We don't I don't I don't see him or talk
to him on his
>> but still be like you know him and my
wife him and my wife used to get along
and we used to watch film together and
I'm like all right let's see how how
well Larry remembers
>> I didn't know how well I'd be received
>> we're walking down the hallway and we're
maybe 20 yards away from him and Larry
sees Matt and he starts smiling and
waving right away. All right. So he
wasn't lying. He wasn't exaggerating.
They are they are buddies.
>> Yeah.
>> He was happy to see you and I think
everybody on Twitter and social media
got a kick out of how you're the same
height as Larry Fitzgerald. Everyone was
like, "Wow, how tall is Matt?"
>> That that was kind of odd because the
picture you took the pictures and I look
a lot taller than him or noticeably
taller than him and I'm not. And so like
a nerd, I looked up Larry Fitzgerald
combine measurements.
>> Yep.
>> And he was 6027, which is 62 and 78. So
just a shade under 63,
>> which is exactly what I am. And I'm
like, there's no way. I mean that I look
people are like, "That looks like he's
6'5. I didn't realize what a giant." I'm
not 6'5. Yeah, it's just a weird
picture, I guess, or whatever. Yeah.
>> 63 in shoes.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh my hair was standing up from wearing
a headset all day, right?
>> Before we go, you were always looking
You were always looking tiptop there,
Matt Williamson.
>> Oh, but also flag. I want to mention I
love that women get to be involved in a
great sport. I mean, yeah. I mean, it I
don't know if one day they'll wear
helmets and pads and play this version
of football or not, but it's great that
they, you know, a whole new realm of
young women and people are going to be
exposed to this in a in a professional
manner. You know,
>> it's great. Uh, last thing before we get
to break and uh and to our buddy Allen
Saunders of Steelers Now to kick off our
bonus third hour. I've been keeping an
eye on this all day, Matt, because
remember Jer McCoy, cornerback out of
Tennessee. Oh, that's
>> one of the more intriguing prospects
proday in Knoxville in Tennessee. Uh,
just within the past hour,
>> he just ran a 4.3840.
>> Oh, good for
>> 38 inch vertical jump. Okay.
>> And a 107 broad jump about a half an
hour ago at his pro.
>> That's more than just checking the boxes
of your healthy
>> first round pick.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> I mean, he probably always was going to
be a firstrounder, but maybe now in the
in the top 10, top 15.
>> Yeah. I originally thought maybe he goes
to a bad team, you know, like the Jets
that can just wait on him and be the
eventual sauce replacement at like 17 or
whatever that is. Now, does he challenge
Delane to be cornerback one?
>> He just might.
>> I mean, I think it's not crazy.
>> He just might. Good day. Uh good day for
Jam McCoy for sure. It's been a good day
for us so far. And when we return, we
will kick off our bonus hour with our
friend Alan Saunders of Steelers. Now
we'll cover all the moving and shaking
here on the grounds of the Builtmore on
this Tuesday with Allen in hour number
three. Wes Schuler Matt Williamson. It
is the drive. Steelers Nation radio on
the Steelers Audio Network.
bonus hour, final hour here of the drive
on location inside the Builtmore in
Phoenix, Arizona for the 2026 NFL League
owners meetings. And joining us now to
kick off our final hour, he's been a
guest few times here in the last few
months on the drive, it's our buddy Alan
Saunders, of course, of Steelers Now.
Allan, uh, this is my first owners
meeting. I have been pleasantly
surprised. This is a fabulous event. How
have things been on your end?
>> It's wonderful every year. I think this
is the best location. I love it here.
>> You like it better in Florida?
>> Yeah, I do. Uh it doesn't rain here. Uh
that's a good point.
>> It's um
>> it is hot. It it the got off the plane
and it's just like who turned they the
furnace on like gee at night and
everything's rough that way too.
>> Still hot. But I uh I think this is a
great setup here and uh they take great
care of us and yeah, really nothing to
complain about this week.
>> Had a good time last night.
>> Yeah, he had a good time.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It's hard not to. So, let's
get right into it with you here, Allan.
And, uh, I know we kind of had some some
news in the the last half an hour or so,
but the NFL owners approving a rule
change allowing the league to step in
and assist on potential
disqualifications,
whether for flagrant football acts or
non-OOT acts, and initiate a flag if one
wasn't thrown. Uh, was the DK Metaf
incident in Detroit last year a real
catalyst of this conversation?
>> I think it was. Uh, it certainly is the
example case for how the NFL would like
this to play out differently. And
honestly, I think, you know, when when
we saw the suspension handed out last
year as two games and then DK went to
the appeal, I thought, ah, you know,
they'll probably knock it down to one.
>> And I think um, you know, maybe if he
had been ejected at halftime of that
game instead of playing the second half,
that might have been something that
happened. So I think in some ways,
you know, I I don't love the idea of of
the the flag from the from the press
box, right? From from then New York
clunky New York throws the flag on the
play.
>> I I think that's that's a little bit
fraught, but I think it will end up
helping resolve situ like it's such a
weird and unique situation. I just hope
they don't overuse it. Like how many
times
>> has a situation like that occurred where
>> you know you're sitting there watching
something happen I really probably
should be thrown out for that and and
and the officials didn't see it like it
it doesn't happen very often.
>> Were there any shocks of the things that
got voted? I mean I thought all the
kickoff stuff was pretty much cut and
dry easy decisions.
>> Yeah. Uh, I'm interested to see. I felt
like this this kickoff they were very
conservative with the roll out of the
the new kickoff where I think we're
going to see as they continue to tweak
this, we're seeing more returns.
>> Certainly. That's what they want. Yeah,
>> we're seeing more returns. It's a play
that exists again, but we're not seeing
anywhere near the explosive plays that
we saw at the height of the kick return
in the in the early 2000s. I think I
wrote there were uh a handful of
touchdowns last year. I think that maybe
maybe six. I think
>> uh there were in 2007 there were two
guys that had three.
>> Wow.
>> The whole league had six.
>> So it's like
>> they got to find
>> Dante Hall Deon Hers.
>> They got to find some ways to give the
return team a chance to make a big play.
And so giving them more flexibility in
where they line the guys up, I think is
what they're going for. or the I mean
the other rest of it just seems very cut
and dry,
>> pretty obvious.
>> Yeah.
>> So like an underrated need I think that
I've been talking about for months and
even before this Steelers really could
use return guys
>> both punt and kick.
>> Yeah, they don't really punt. I mean
Jaylen Warren I assume will continue to
be one of the two guys back there on
kickoff return probably but uh Kenny
Gainwell was there, you know. Um, uh,
yeah, I think and Mike McCarthy was
talking yesterday about he wants wide
receivers that can do more than one
thing. And he he very specifically said,
yeah, that could mean playing in the
slot or playing outside. It could also
mean go play on special teams and
>> returner, gunner, or whatever.
>> They don't have a lot of bodies in the
wide receiver room. So, I think it makes
sense if you're looking at mid-round
picks, say, "Oh, go get another wide
receiver who can return some kicks."
Mhm.
>> Well, if you're kind of trying to read
the tea leaves of of the draft here in
what 23 days it it kicks off in
Pittsburgh.
Uh Mike McCarthy spent some time this
morning talking about the value of
position flexibility, particularly how
critical it is for an offensive line.
There are a lot of those uh uh you know
first round type prospects in this draft
and even some into the second round that
kind of profile as they could play guard
or tackle in the league. Does that kind
of does that put an antenna up? Does
that feel like a real option for the
Steelers to go back to the offensive
line at 21 even when they've invested a
lot of draft capital there recently?
>> I don't know that I see the player that
I think is a fit that's going to be
there at 21. I mean, Vega Yane I love as
a player, but I I mean
>> I would be surprised if he even gets to
18 and and he's a guard and a really
good one. Um,
>> in terms of like some of the other guys,
I I just don't know. I you know I think
versatility is great. I think also
versatility is something we say about
people that we're not sure if they have
a home and and like don't get those
things confused. Like is Kaden Proctctor
a tackle who might have to move to guard
or is he just not a very good tackle?
>> I don't know. Yeah.
And I don't want to draft a guy in the
first round that might not be a very
good tackle and I don't have any idea if
he's going to move to guard. I think
we've seen a trend in recent years of
some of these guys that know that
question is coming when they get to the
NFL, they've moved to guard on their own
in in their in college. And I think
that's probably the better way to go for
it. You know, like I said, versatility
is great. If you have it is very rare
though that you have guys that are truly
good at multiple positions. Most of the
time you're either talking about guys
who are just okay at everything or guys
that really just don't have a fit. So,
another I think we can all agree that
they're going to draft a receiver high
and maybe even two of them, you know, in
this draft with all the picks they have.
>> I really think there's about a 0% chance
Tate from Ohio State is there.
>> I think everyone else has I think
everyone else has a chance to be make
21. Do you have a a second favorite? Do
you have a pecking order of the
receivers that you like? Have you ranked
them in any way?
>> I actually think I like Tyson better
than Tate. Do you
>> on tape? It's just the injuries that is
a big factor. You can't really
>> uh you know it's it's hard to factor
what teams are gonna especially with his
because it's not like he has something
that's ongoing. It's just that he's been
hurt all the time. It's durability and
um I don't know how to weight that. I
love his tape. I think to me he's
clearly the second guy that I would
want. But I I mean I I don't think it's
crazy that the one of those top guys is
there for the Steelers at 21. I think
it's very likely given that they have 12
picks that if one of those guys even
makes it to a short tradeup range,
three, four picks up that they'll go get
them because why not with 12? I mean,
you're not going to have 12 rookies make
the team.
>> No. Do you feel strongly about Boston or
Conpion or Lemon or any of those others?
>> I think Boston for me, I love him as a
player. Uh does feels like the worst fit
for the Steelers. I mean, just a little
too redundant.
>> He is exactly Well, I mean, Mike's just
talking about guys who wanted guys who
can do multiple things. I don't think
he's that. And the one thing he does,
they they already have guys that can do
that. I just think
>> he's
>> the traditional outside the numbers.
Yeah.
>> He's he's probably the worst fit. I
think he's a really good player and and
decent chance that he's BPA when pick 21
comes around. I think I would rather
have if I was like making a big board
sort of for any team, I'd put him ahead
of Conpsion and Cooper, but I think
they're better fits for what the
Steelers need right now.
>> Okay, Alan Saunders of Steelers Now with
us here on our little mini radio row at
the league meetings inside the
Builtmore. Um Allan, you know, sticking
with that with that draft conversation,
you mentioned those 12 picks. Is there a
sweet spot for the Steelers to move up?
Like, would you be interested in maybe
nabbing an additional second round pick?
Is there any thought in your mind even
from potentially moving down to 21 if
there's not the the BPA fit uh that you
love as well?
>> Yeah, I think the the best part of this
draft for me is from about pick
15 to 60. I really like those guys. So
whether it's moving up a little bit in
the first round, um moving up in the
second round, I love the players in the
40 range if they can get into there
>> or moving up to get another second round
pick. I think all those should be on the
table. Those feel like
>> the best ways to use those additional
resources. I'm sure they would also be
interested in trading some of them for
27 capital. Usually you profit on that
exchange by waiting a year,
>> but I think in this situation that's not
going to be the case. Uh talking to
>> you're dumping a late third. You're not
going to get an early second next year.
I
>> I think every team would like to move
some draft capital from 26 to 27. And
you got to have somebody willing to come
the other way to make it happen. Wes, I
don't think we've talked about this lat
at all, but I think it's more likely
they move from 53 or wherever they pick
in the second up to 40 than they move
from 21 to 17. It'd be a lot less
expensive. You might get your cake and
eat it too with the receiver lineman
situation with a a pick at, you know, 21
and 40 and maybe it only cost you a
fourth or a late third or someone throws
in a fifth next year or whatever. You
know, I I just think you could end up
with two guys with similar grades.
>> Yeah, I think that's and the Steelers
have, I would say, been pretty good
under uh Omar Khan at finding those guys
that are falling down the board
>> and and and getting themselves in
position to meet them where they are.
And and I think that you you know
>> that's that to me is like his hidden
skill as a general manager. really good
at it
>> is that he's very good at understanding
how the rest of the league is going to
value players and and find the the value
picks and so yeah absolutely they may
not even have to get very far up from
that 53 pick to get a guy that we're
talking about as a borderline first
round player
>> I could absolutely see that happening
and I've been thinking about it more and
more just the last 48 hours
>> all right we did it we made it over 10
minutes into this uh segment without
asking you about Aaron Rogers but now
gez now now we have to ask about Aaron
Rogers. Uh any change in uh what Mike
McCarthy had to say this morning in your
mind? Do you still do you have any
timeline on this or is this just one of
those we got to wait and see and and we
won't know until we know?
>> Yeah, I mean I think the Steelers are
pretty clearly planning on him being
their quarterback. I don't think they're
really I mean I'm sure they're doing
some due diligence, but I don't think
they're in any hurry on those other
ideas. I don't think there's anybody
else out there that's worth putting a
hard deadline on for. And really, I
mean, I know that that Art said earlier
this week that, you know, he he expects
to know by the draft. It's not like
they're going to change their draft
plans whether they've already signed
Aaron Rogers or not.
>> They're not going to like Tai Simpson
anymore or less. They're not going up to
get Mendoza.
>> No one other than Mendoza. And honestly,
maybe not even Mendoza in this draft
class should be playing this year in my
opinion. So like it doesn't like it's
completely separate conversation really
until you start missing OTAA sessions
nothing really matters. So I mean to me
that's the that's the first time that it
becomes an issue.
>> Yeah. And I think I've asked every one
of our guests for the last week or so
this exact same question because I
always preface it the same way. I can
make a really strong case yes or I can
make a really strong case no. the third
to fifth round quarterback pile, the
Becks, the Nusmeers, I mean Aller,
whoever you like.
>> Should you do even bother or are you a
yay or nay on that? Um, well, I think
there are about
maybe three guys that I think are down
there that have traits that are worth
taking a flyer on.
>> I keep going back to Cole Payton. I
think if you don't have upside, it's not
worth just drafting a guy who's probably
a backup. I I would not do that.
>> Yes, I agree.
>> I think there are a couple guys
>> That's my problem with Beck.
>> Yeah, I just don't think Beck has the
physical tools. Uh I think Aller does. I
would take him, but maybe not. Like he's
mostly mocked in like the third round.
Feels a little rich for me, but I think
he's at least like a gamble worth
taking. Payton is interesting. I'm not
sure he's actually very like I didn't
love him at the Senior Bowl. Thought he
was just okay.
>> He doesn't throw the football great.
>> No. And uh I think Tayen Green is
interesting because just he's such a
good athlete that you know you can run
the tush push with him and you can do
some Taesm Hill stuff with him and maybe
it never works out but if you're talking
about a fourth or fifth round pick and
that's all he becomes like that's not
the end of the world.
>> Yeah. Yeah. But I just like I don't
think they necessarily need like a body.
No,
>> you know,
>> I mean that probably means that Rudolph
gets let go if you do that or some way
in some way.
>> Well, I mean like how many of those guys
are going to be better than Mason
Rudolph? Like half
>> probably none immediately.
>> Yeah. None immediately and maybe half
ever. Like so
>> to me that's not a
>> I I mean hearing Mike talk I think
they're going to try to draft one but I
seems that way. I don't see that there's
like this pressing like you know I think
my mock drafts I've kind of gone back
and forth where some of them I'll have
one and then some of them I don't
>> I I am really exactly on the fence you
know like you might get Dak Prescott or
Perie I mean you might yeah you know but
you no way knowing but trying but I
can't say I'm doing cartwheels over the
idea either or and that's taken away
from reps that Rudolph's going to get or
Howard's going to get. Yeah, but not if
they're just coming at the expense of
Rudolph because, you know, he's probably
gonna get reps, too. I don't know. I
think
>> I I think the Howard thing is
interesting. Mike very, you know,
strongly stating his case today for why
he thinks Will Howard has the trades to
be a future starting quarterback. But
also,
>> do you believe that?
>> I mean, I do. Um, you know, he
>> seems a little over the top to me. Yeah,
I I believe it because he's given us
some some background at least um for for
why he thinks that now said yesterday,
you know, he gave this long sort of diet
tribe about uh playing in cold weather
and there's certain things that he wants
and he wants size and he wants arm
length and hand size. Oh, Will's hand
size, I think, is pretty average, but
he's a tall guy. He's a big guy, long
arm, he's a physical presence, strong,
right? Like you can He played in the
cold in college. Uh, and so you can kind
of see him checking those boxes
>> in the way that that Mike described. So
I kind of buy it, but I think there are
also like it's two different it's it's
one thing to say he has starting
quarterback traits. Okay, fine. Like
it's it's also like a 2% chance. Maybe
you want to find out about that 2%
chance. Maybe you're intrigued by it,
but I think they're also realistic
enough that hey, take take another shot
if you can. Like it's not it's not like
this is some kind of sure thing. Mhm.
That's an interesting conversation.
>> Allan, last one I've got for you is uh
Mike McCarthy kind of saying the right
things and and in positive conversation
about Caleb Williams or Caleb Williams,
pardon me, Caleb Johnson and Roman
Wilson. Uh which of those two do you
think has the better shot to carve out a
role under this new regime?
>> That's a tough way to phrase that. I'm
not overly bullish on either of their
chances as we sit here right now. I
think I mean Caleb just feels very boxed
out of reps. Like I I don't know where
the opportunity comes. He pretty much
needs somebody to get hurt at this
point.
>> And I think
>> there's at least more roster spots at
the receiver position.
>> And I think he will run the ball very
very well when he finally gets an
opportunity to do so. I have never had a
doubt about Caleb Johnson's ability as a
ball carrier. Pass protection, route
running, his hands. I I have questions.
Obviously, special teams didn't go great
last year, but I think if if they needed
him, if somebody gets hurt and they need
him to go have, you know, five to 10
carries a game, I think he could be very
good in that role. Uh Roman Wilson, I I
don't think is a very good fit for this
offense. Uh he doesn't really do those
multiple things that Mike McCarthy was
talking about. I think he would best be
pigeonhold as a slot receiver somewhere.
And I think his traits that he brought
to the table, the things you saw at
Michigan that made him the draft pick
that he became is toughness,
physicality, run blocking, ability, a
willingness to go over the middle, but
he is not this sort of precise route
runner technician that you associate
with a West Coast offense slot receiver.
So, I think this scheme is going to be a
worse fit for him. But I do think there
is always a a sort of and Mike had a
great quote about it. You know, it's he
said it's the Catholic operation. Say
three Hail Marys and the priest absolves
you and your slate clean.
>> Yeah. And you get a clean slate. It's
like I I think that's true, but like I I
don't I don't know where the role comes
from for either of those guys really. I
think Roman has a bigger opportunity.
Obviously, there's just much less depth
at wide receiver.
>> I have one last thing for you. Like I'm
going to assume especially with the
number of picks they have, they're going
to draft at least one defensive back of
some shape, size, or whatever. Free
safety, strong safety, nickel, big corn,
you know, outside guy, nick, small
nickel, big nickel, whatever. What style
do you think they're looking for first
and foremost to add to the secondary?
>> I really don't know. I mean, I think
that
>> a lot of this is what do you do with
Ramsey?
>> I think the signing of Jamal Dean tells
me that they want to play manto man.
They want to have the ability to play
manto man
>> with size.
>> And I think they probably don't have
anyone certainly don't have anyone long
term and I don't even know if they have
anybody in short term that you can say
okay go in the slot and cover Z Flowers
manto man. To me that's the thing
they're lacking. I also think it's a
really good slot corner draft.
>> I really like the day two guys that are
slot corners. And so to me that feels
like the biggest thing that they don't
have that will be.
>> And then you think say Ramsay becomes
more safety first.
>> Well, I just think for this year it
could be a small role. It could just be,
hey, you're the nickel when we're
playing Baltimore because it's Zay
Flowers. And then when you go play
Graham is very weak to
>> and when you go play somebody else who
plays all 12 personnel and it's a 6'5
tight end in there. Okay, then maybe it
needs to be forget Ramsey, maybe it
needs to be Deshawn Elliott, whatever,
you know. Uh but Right. Yeah.
>> It would be a it could be a small part
at first and then you see how things go
and then hey, if it's a young guy who's
who looks like he's deserving more
playing time, then sure, you can let
Brisker walk away and you could move
Ramsay to safety full time. But I think
that's an area where that's the one
thing in the secondary I really don't
think they have where you feel really
good about okay like manto man in this
situation. They they kind of have all
the other boxes checked.
>> Great stuff with our buddy Allen
Saunders. Make sure you're checking out
all his coverage this week and always
steelers.com. Thanks for taking the
time, dude. Appreciate it.
>> Thanks, fellas.
>> Don't uh don't melt too much out there
on us now. All right.
>> I'll try.
>> Two more segments to go for our league
owners meeting coverage. We will
continue. We'll get to some of your
tweets and uh and some of the final
proceedings of the day. Wesler, Matt
Williamson. It is the drive. Steelers
Nation radio on the Steelers Audio
Network.
It is our penultimate segment here of
our league owners meeting coverage. Wes
jeweler and Matt Williamson inside the
built more. You know the drill. Phoenix,
Arizona
here. Our final hour of coverage. It's
been a fun few days and uh we've had
some great guests and some great
conversation. A lot of different We've
touched on a lot of different bases here
at M today. Steeler stuff, national
stuff, league stuff, draft stuff. I uh I
always enjoy these uh these type of uh
events where we get to uh go over and
kind of cover so much different ground.
And you told me you had some uh some
more draft stuff, some Todd McShay stuff
that you wanted us to discuss here
before we depart Arizona.
>> So I firmly believe that this is a weird
year for the first round, especially the
first half of the first round. the lack
of great premium positions or a
multitude of f obvious first round
quarterbacks. I mean, there's not a lot
of blue chip dudes. I think there's less
surefire first rounders than any other
year. And I've been thinking very much
along the lines of how's the NFL going
to respond to that? And I was listening
to I mentioned Mcshay because frankly
the way he put it was better than the
way I put it because I've been thinking
the exact same thing that after Mendoza
goes of course you know and whatnot. I
think the league is just going to be
happy
finding
quality players at the next premium
positions. Okay. And what I mean by that
is again I think there's one quarterback
that's guaranteed to be a first round
pick. Simpson will figure it out or
whatever. He's a wild card. I still
think the tackles are going to go. I
still think the edge defensive end type
guys are going to go because they're
just the hardest positions to find
>> cornerbacks.
>> Yeah. But especially those two. And Todd
really put it out the same way. and he
said, you know, I've been talking to
people in the league and he thinks that
a leaguewide trend will just be like,
get me a quality starter for four or
five years that's cheap at defensive end
and tackle so I don't have to pay one,
even if they don't turn into Bosa or
Pennul or whatever. Just give me the
>> the best move economically.
>> And it's pretty good draft to do that in
the first round. There's a lot of these
edges and there's definitely a lot of
these tackles that again aren't Bosa or
Alt, but they're going to go in the
first round. And what Todd the way, and
why I say Todd said it better than me,
was he started laying out the names and
we could pull up any list, you know,
sure, you know, any, you know, Daniel
Jeremiah's top 50 or whatever. And
frankly, I don't even care about the
names, but I think he's certain that
there will be at least 13 edges and
tackles combined.
>> Okay.
>> And maybe as many as 15. Probably
between 13 and 15. Those two positions
added together. TJ Parker, etc.
>> One of those positions, the Steelers
want all them to fall. You know, Blake
Miller is not a name we mentioned, but
he's like, he's going in the first
round. He's a tackle. Maybe it's not at
the very beginning of the first round.
>> The kid out of Clemson. Yeah,
>> kid out of Clemson. You know, but you
know, if you pull up Todd's top six or
seven tackles, he thinks they're all
going in the first round. If you pull up
his six or seven edges, just give us the
names if you don't mind. You're looking
at them.
>> Yeah. So, obviously Arville Reese, David
Bailey, Francis Maui Goa, Ruben Bane
Jr., Spencer Fanu, Monroe Fielding,
Hakee Meador, Kendrick Faulk. We've
talked about all those guys. TJ Parker,
Blake Miller, Caleb Blomu, uh, uh, Gabe,
is it it's Akis, right?
>> Yeah, I think that's the first name
that's not guaranteed to be a
firstrounder. I think all those other
guys overall. Zion Young, Cashas, how
Kaden Proctor, Maxore,
Malachi Lawrence. I mean, he's got M all
those guys are in his top 50 of his big
board that I just every single one of
those guys. And then R.M. Mason Thomas
51. I mean,
>> so side note, Todd, you know, he gets a
lot of information and he said he thinks
the Browns are infatuated with Proctor
and might even take him in the top 10,
let alone if he gets to the their second
pick. Right. Right. Right.
>> So,
you can get pretty easily to 15 when you
combine those two positions. And here's
where I'm going with this. There's only
32 picks in the first round. If 15 of
them are edge and tackles,
>> Mendoza
>> makes it 16.
>> Jeremiah Love 17.
>> Love 17.
>> Uh,
>> Caleb DS.
>> I was just going to go stay on offense.
>> Okay.
>> Guard out of uh Ioni.
>> Yep. Wenger Yawan out of Penn State.
>> 17. Is that where we're at?
>> Yep.
>> Sadique.
>> 18.
>> Tate,
>> I think so. obviously run 19
>> and I'll come back to receiver in a
minute. That's why I'm h doing this
whole conversation. So, we're already in
19 names with those two positions in
offense.
>> I don't know that there's a defensive
tackle that's guaranteed.
>> I would be shocked if there was one that
goes in the top 20.
>> Me, too. Me, the edge guys who are
already off the board, but Styles is
going.
>> Yes. Downs is going.
>> Maybe another linebacker
>> perhaps,
>> but probably not. Styles is for sure. Or
does that get us to 21? I lost 21. Okay.
>> Downs gets us to 22.
>> Or sorry. No, I was including Styles and
Downs. Sorry. Cuz that was 20 and 21.
>> Thean's going to go in the first round.
>> Yes, he is.
>> Maybe uh the Toledo dude. That gets us
to
>> Emanuel McNeel Warren.
>> Yeah,
>> that gets us to 23 or 24. I lost count.
I've been bad about this exercise.
>> McCoy is definitely going now.
>> Yes.
>> The lane's definitely going now.
>> Maybe corner three. I'd be shocked if
there's only two corners drafted in the
first round. So, where I'm going with
this is I have not talked about quote
the other receivers not named Tate yet.
>> And I've already got to like 27 or 28
definite firstrounders,
>> which then tells you if you pull up just
his receiver board or any receiver board
and you only take Tate out of the
equation,
>> you got
>> there's like a dozen awesome ones left,
you know? So that's kind of what I've
been thinking with the Steelers is
everyone knows that I've been leaning in
a vacuum. I would take O line at 21 over
wide receiver at 21 unless one is a much
better grade than the other of course in
a pie in the sky scenario,
>> right? Give me one of those tackles that
everyone's coveting and they'll be we
know one of them will be there at 21. It
probably won't be freeling or I don't
even care which one it is. I mean I
inure
>> there'll probably be more than one at
21.
>> Yeah. And then the first run round ends
on Thursday and maybe there's only two
or three receivers off the board, but
there's still like nine more that you
would love
>> love that you can just hang there at 53
and maybe get the one that falls to you
or what I mentioned before,
>> scooch up like six picks and get the one
you want.
>> I mean, like if you look at it through
that lens,
>> it's very doable. It's very doable to
get two guys that maybe you would even
consider a 21 or a 28 if you traded down
or whatever. You know what I mean? It
doesn't have to be Iron Shore or whoever
my favorite one is. It's just the way
that's what these teams do. Would you
rather take Boston there and see what's
left at O line oris
>> or would you take Fu or you know
>> and then see what's see what's left in
the wide receiver
>> cup
>> and think you know and Allan mentioned
this too Omar's so good at knowing what
the league covets but so much of it
comes down to money teams are going to
take edges and tackles because you can't
get them
>> they're cost they're cost controlled for
four or five
>> if everybody in the first round's kind
of the same just give me an edge or
tackle
>> position of value.
>> Thus, receivers should fall. They should
be the position that falls.
>> I I am I am the bottom line. That's the
bottom line of all this.
>> I did all this like math and blah blah
blah. And
>> well, you showed your work. That's what
teachers always want you to do in school
is show your work.
>> Then you draw the line under and the
answer to this whole segment is
receivers should fall.
>> So get them,
>> which is which would be a great outcome.
>> This is that's I hope the Steelers see
the same way. If that's your Oenheimer
equation for this entire draft, is E=
MC², that's Einstein, not Oppenheimer,
you get it. Just let me go. Science
wasn't exactly my bag. The end result is
distilled down to wide receivers fall
down the board. Maybe you get to pick 21
and Tate is the only one off the board.
Or maybe Tate and one or something,
right? There's two gone, you know, but
there's still 14 you like or 12 you like
to start.
>> So, do you leave that on pause and take
the offensive line? take the they check
that box because it's going to be harder
to find
>> or do you go but yeah but look at the
high-end wide receiver we could nab
right now that be another thought you
might get wide receiver three at 21
where you thought that was no chance so
if you're in love with you know he
mentioned Tyson yeah he he likes Tyson
okay fine you know
>> but the more you lay it out
>> economics rule this league so much
>> so much and especially with the Steelers
current general manager exactly that's
where that's where he cut his teeth in
this in this He's going to have a feel
for where these guys go. And the way
that Todd laid it out in the podcast I
was listening to, I'm like, "This really
benefits the Steelers."
>> Yes.
>> Yeah,
>> that makes a ton of sense. And I'm glad
you kind of gave me a
>> Hey, when we were doing our again, as we
always share,
>> I don't want to wait till Friday to have
this conversation cuz fresh on my mind
>> or these uh you know, these very
extensive our pre-production show
meetings that are very extensive and
very detailed. You uh you you you nudged
me in the ribs this morning and you go,
"Hey, at some point today, let's talk
about this this Todd McShet thing. No
idea what I'm even talking about. I'm
like, just give me a segment. I'll we'll
figure it out. You know,
>> I think it worked out pretty well.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. But I hope I laid that
out for our viewers why you do it the
order you do it and why the le wrestle
league could really play into your hand.
>> And we have talked a lot about how it is
not the uh perceived as the strongest
draft class, you know, in recent
history, but there's a lot of tackles.
There's a lot of edge rushers.
>> Yeah. You want the edges to go.
>> That's the other than quarterback. Those
are the two most valuable positions.
>> Yeah. And you want to be shopping in
that, you know, you you're probably
going to add a offensive lineman of note
and there's a lot to pick from. There's
a lot of edges and you want them to go,
you know, especially before you become
in the market for your second position
and they will,
>> you know,
>> because they always do
>> real quick. I mean, history shows
tackles and edges don't last anyway.
>> Exactly. Right. And so, let's assume
that that's going to be the case again.
>> Um, and pick 21 rolls around. Uh, are
would you be gung-ho to go and get wide
receiver two or three? Would you say
>> I still would rather take the O line?
>> You'd still rather take the O lineman
>> unless the grades are unless they're in
two different tiers.
>> Of course.
>> You know, if they're in two different
tiers, great. You're happy that that
guy's that the higher tier players are
still available. That's easy.
>> And then you'll say, "We're still going
to get a wide receiver that we really
like at 53."
>> Yeah. Or 42.
>> Sure. You know, 46.
>> Two or three of them go at the beginning
of Friday and you're like, "H, I don't
like the the the way this is going. I'll
take dump one of my third rounders and
go get Cooper who happens to be their
36.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Because he didn't go in round one
like everyone thinks he was. That that
that I guess that's also part of the
when you draw the line at the end of the
equation. A lot of these mock drafts
have Cooper and Conpsion and guys I like
a lot.
>> We've seen some that have had six wide
receivers in the first round.
>> That's not going to happen.
>> I believe now that's not going to
happen. It's going to be closer to three
than five just cuz you get to 32 pretty
quick.
>> You sure do.
>> Downs is going, you know, Theman's
going. uh Iion's going. Not to mention
Mendoza.
>> If 15 edges and tackles go, that's half
the first round.
>> You know what I mean? I mean, there's
only 32 going.
>> And some of those will go after 21. But
still,
>> of course. Of course.
>> If 12 of the 15 or 11 of the 15 are in
the top 20,
>> right?
>> And that'd be a good place to be for for
>> you know, Downs and Styles and Mendoza
and Love were going to be one of them.
>> Absolute locks.
>> And uh what's his face?
Uh I don't know if he's a lock before
20, but the wide receiver from Ohio
State is Tates definitely is, you know,
>> and I'm starting to think Jam McCoy and
Mansor Delane are as well.
>> Yes. And and they don't hurt you. You
don't you're not counting on them being
there, you know.
>> It's a good place to be.
>> We are what?
>> I hope it made sense.
>> Totally made sense. And we're 23 days
away from seeing how that uh will
potentially all play out. We've got to
take our final break here. When we
return on the other side, we will ride
this thing out with your questions, your
comments, your concerns, your reaction.
It'll be uh it'll be the X Twitter
segment as our buddy Dale Loi would have
called it. And that will be our final
proceeding here from inside the
Builtmore in Phoenix, Arizona. Wesler
and Matt Williamson of course on
location for the NFL league meetings. It
is the drive Steelers Nation radio on
the Steelers Audio Network.
It is our final segment here from our
well I guess March home Matt, right?
>> I suppose. Yeah. End of March.
>> If Indianapolis is our February home and
Lrobe is our summer home. There you go.
I guess this is our spring break home.
>> We definitely have a summer home.
>> We certainly do. It's Sharkies.
>> These are vacations.
>> That's right. This is spring break.
Spring break. It's been a nice little
spring break. Man, it's been a lot of
fun. I know we've said that a bunch of
times. It's a different vibe since our
last segment. I'll just reiterate it one
time because this is my first time doing
this is I kind of shared with you this
was like the last thing in the NFL
calendar for me to check off in terms of
things that I've done.
>> Yeah.
>> Done the combine a bunch of times,
training camps. You know, I think we
went over this conversation. I've been
to now 23 of the 30 NFL stadiums. I've
done international games. I got to do a
Super Bowl and radio row and all that
when I was with the Eagles back in 2018.
But I have never in my let's see here
total it has been 11 years working in
the NFL between three with the Eagles
and eight with the Steelers so far. I
had never done an owners meeting and uh
and this was this was pretty stinking
cool.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I I I I think I kind of laid
it out to you but it's hard to explain.
I mean even like when Dale would explain
it to me or you know other folks and you
spend a few days here and it is just a
different vibe. you know, it's not
nearly the hustle and bustle of the
combine, but there is a lot of action
and things happen while you're here.
Rule changes and whatnot, you know,
>> and they uh not that they treat us
poorly at the combine, but they treat
you like the prom king here compared to
way better here in terms of service and
whatnot.
>> There's just food at the And we've we've
get like a water.
>> We've shared these stories before. For
us to get just a bottle of water at the
combine is like a 15minute roundtrip
walk,
>> which you can't really do during a
4minute commercial break.
>> Exactly. Um, so here, man, there's
coffee and drink and food everywhere.
They treat you very well. The dinner
last night, the the swag bags of all
kinds of Nike and new era stuff.
>> It's upper upper class.
>> It It is It is certainly I feel like a
1enter. I'm going to walk around with my
pinky up the the rest of the day here
until we leave tomorrow. But before we
close down the day's proceedings, you
all know how we end things this time of
year. Let's get to some of your
questions, comments, concerns, reactions
of course on on X on Twitter, the X
Twitter as Dale would call it. Uh
Williamson NFL Wesleyer is where you can
participate with the show today,
tomorrow, all the time, whenever you
want to. Ian tweet, although not
tomorrow because we won't have a show
tomorrow. We'll be traveling. Ian tweets
and says, "Gentlemen, hope you're
enjoying the dry heat down there in
Arizona. on the uh Pat McAfee show, Mike
McCarthy said that they were planning on
going to six pro days but only made one.
Does this bother you at all for the
overall draft process?
>> First I heard that. Um not really.
>> Yeah, I don't know if it bothers me. I
mean, I I wish they could have gone to
as many as they wanted to, but
>> Yeah, that doesn't mean no one was in
attendance. I mean, they could have had
area scouts their quarterback coaches,
which I'm sure they did.
>> I'm sure they did.
>> When he says they, he probably means him
and Omar. I would
>> That's what I was going to say. I'm not
sure who he exactly means by that. Um,
couple notes. I don't know if everyone
knows this, but all the pro days are
videoed and sent to every team. So, you
can watch everything that happened
there. You can't pull back the curtain
and chat with people and learn some
things here and there if you're not
there obviously, you know, or see your
buddy and be like, "What do you think of
this Tai Simpson guy or whatever, you
know?" I mean, so I guess there's a
little bit lost in that. Um, but again,
I'm sure somebody was in attendance, but
I guess it is there's more cache if it's
a head coach and GM there. Um, I assume
Ohio State was the only one.
>> I would think so.
>> I thought Georgia was one that they were
talking about. I don't know. I'm
guessing on that. Um, however, what
always blew me away over the years was
the Steelers were so well known for
taking guys out to dinner the night
before their combine.
>> That's the Mike Tomlin thing.
>> And I never knew how they pulled it off.
You're like, "How do they take six
Michigan dudes out to dinner when the 31
other teams are like, "Hey, I'd like to
do that, too."
>> Because they'd all like to go dine with
Mike Tomlin,
>> I guess. And I I'm sure some of them
went from the Steelers one to the Bears
one or whatever, too, you know, and
maybe just didn't eat or had dessert or
whatever.
>> One place.
>> Yeah. Shook a hand or whatever.
>> But still, if you're taking several
dudes out, like I know the Iowa one with
like Jack Campbell and those guys, he
had four or five of all the top picks.
Are the Steelers losing that? I have no
idea. I never knew how it worked to
begin with or how they pulled it off to
begin with.
>> Some of that behind the-scenes stuff
that unless you
>> There's definitely advantages.
>> No, there certainly is.
>> Scouting is, you know, private
investigating in some way, you know,
>> but as you mentioned, there is so much
video and information readily available
in in this modern era as well.
>> You're going to see every throw and
every route and every, you know, test
>> result and all that stuff.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Michael Adesso tweets
us and says, "Okay, guys, let's talk
offball linebacker. After this season,
only Pton Wilson and Carson Bruner are
under contract. They've had numerous
contact with prospects in the draft. If
you uh read the reports, especially top
ones, uh Tony Pauline has said they love
CJ Allen and they were at the Georgia
Proday. Uh Jacob Rodriguez from Texas
Tech. I know most fans and uh maybe even
you guys probably wouldn't want to draft
a linebacker in round one, but I think
it's at least worth a discussion because
I think it's plausible and certainly
plausible in their top 100 picks.
>> Well, definitely in the top 100. You've
got five. You've got five of those.
>> I think I'd be shocked if it was in
round one, but everything you say is
correct about the quality of that's one
of the positions that if you ask people
to list the strengths in this draft,
that comes up quickly.
>> It does. And and there are multiple
round one options. Um, and Michael knows
his stuff. He tweets us all the time.
Um,
it's an odd conversation cuz it, let's
say you would go round one, would you
then field option offers for queen?
>> I think you would almost have to.
>> Yeah, I think you'd almost have to if
you go that deep in. What if it's round
two?
Then maybe you just play it out and have
a bunch of guys there and one of them is
a really good special teamer blah blah
blah. Sure,
>> I definitely think you're drafting one.
And I think the third round's probably
when you really start to talk about it
or a slight trade up or something like
that, but
I don't know, I guess, is the answer. I
mean, a lot of these questions rarely do
I answer I don't know.
But there are a lot of them. I would bet
everything I have just about that they
draft a offthe-ball linebacker probably
in the top four rounds no matter what,
which is seven picks. I can't imagine
there being six more needs more than
linebacker.
>> No,
>> I just tend to think it might be next
year's project. You know, and it doesn't
mean you can't reup Queen.
>> Sure.
>> You you know.
>> Hopefully, especially if you know, new
new look, new outcome for him in in
Patrick Graham's defense. Yeah, he might
he might have an outstanding season.
>> And Wilson's not under contract much
longer either.
>> No, this is his last year. Yeah,
>> he's got
>> for Wilson and Well, Wilson and Bruner,
sorry, have one more year.
>> One more. Yeah. Yeah, they'll be back a
year from now, but then correct they're
up.
>> Yes, this time.
>> And Bruner is a different beast. I mean,
he's not you're not even counting on him
to be a linebacker.
>> Yeah.
>> Another one of our regulars, Sudesh,
tweets us and says, "I can't help but
think that Cleveland proposed that
five-year trade rule so they could try
and get more first round picks for Miles
Garrett."
>> Maybe it's still you get plenty in the
next three years.
>> They will get they will if they decide
to move Miles Garrett, they'll they'll
have plenty of first round picks, I
think.
>> Jimbo tweets us and says, "Hey guys, P1
here." Hey, everybody's a P1, baby. I
love it. He said, "I was just able to do
a mock draft. Uh, ended kind of similar
to the one that you guys did last week
with trading back a few times. I was
able to get Philly's 2027 second round
pick and the Jets 20 27 first round
pick. That may be unrealistic, but would
you take it or go fish?" I'll tell you
this right now.
>> Well, those two things are pretty
attractive.
>> I would be willing to do pretty much
anything to get the uh the Jets first
round pick for 27 and an Eagles second
rounder as well.
>> Yeah. And I don't know what he ended up
with. I'm looking at it.
>> He ended up with Max uh Ian Shore at
pick 33 in the second round.
>> Okay.
>> Being the Steelers first.
>> I mean, that sounds wonderful. I mean,
sure, the most valuable asset is the
Jets first round pick next year. I mean,
that's almost guaranteed a top 10 pick.
It might be one.
>> They're not going to trade it no matter
what.
>> I don't think so.
>> There's no chance. I think that's too
unrealist. No way the Jets are moving
their first round pick any way, shape,
or form. I do think it's unrealistic,
but I would definitely be into it if
that was a possibility.
>> I mean, the Jets first round pick next
year is worth more than 21 this year.
>> Michael tweets us and says, "It seems as
though Dylan Cook is a restricted free
agent next off season. Does that alter
any thoughts about needing to draft that
position?" We I don't know, Michael, if
you listened to the show yesterday, but
we kind of actually dug into this a lot.
What you would do with Dylan Cook and
Spencer Anderson. We did that on the
show yesterday and how we talked about
now might be the time to extend those
guys. they get a well-earned pay bump in
a career where they haven't made a ton
of money. Yeah. It gives you some
security going forward, but it also
doesn't you're not marrying them with a
massive contract at the same time. It
just
>> and it doesn't prohibit you from
drafting one high or trying to, you
know, go over them or what you've won
too many offensive linemen. That's not
the worst problem I've ever heard.
>> That's not a problem at all, I don't
think. Um, so we discussed all those
things yesterday, but it would not alter
our thoughts about the needs in the
draft, but we would be very interested
in locking up Dylan Cook and Spencer
Anderson as well for
>> Yeah, I'd like to just
>> Cody tweets us and says, "New mock draft
rule for you guys going forward. You
must take Iowa guard Jennings Dunker on
every mock because with a name like
that, he is a Yinszer fever dream. A
Jennings Dunker out of Iowa. Do you see
how he looked in that Iowa uniform?
>> Right. and he's got the crazy hair and
everybody loves him and he's a good
prospect, but let's not scout on, you
know, what they look like walking in the
room too much. You know, he's not a make
or break player, but he's he's probably
going into round two.
>> Yeah,
>> he might be a tackle. He certainly could
be a guard.
>> Jennings dunker. Well, I watched all his
tape in a big 10, man. He was good. Mr.
Steel City tweets us and says, "Would
you guys say a good comparison for Chris
Brazzle is Marquez Valdez Scantling?"
Obviously, I don't mean the recent
Steelers NBS, but I see some similar
traits from his younger Packer days.
>> Um, much more talented. Valdis
Scantling.
>> Brazzle much more talented. Valdzle is
um they're both 6'4. They both run
really low 44 or four 40 times. Um, but
Brazle's much smoother, much more
athletic in every other trait, more
explosive, better out of his brakes,
better changing direction. Brazle's
closer to Pickins in terms of just
things he was born with.
>> Gotcha. The natural raw ability that you
can't coach.
>> It's really, really high.
>> Eclectic Genius tweets us and says,
>> "Show question for Wes. What are the
ones and twos?" And for Matt, our dear
Craig Wolfley, RIP, used to speculate
that Brick Jones might be a outstanding
guard. What do you think of that for
plan B if he loses the left tackle
competition? It could factor in.
>> You've brought that up a few times this
this off season. Um,
>> if your best five is Cook at left tackle
and Jones at left guard,
>> I would say experiment with it at camp.
>> Understand you'd be asking him to play
what, a third different position in four
years. But
>> I think
>> he might find a home.
>> He might find a home. Really excel.
>> The ones and twos get on the field.
>> That the ones and twos is an old name
from I say people don't know
>> from the turntable days, right? where
you had two sets of vinyl and you had
your mixer and that was the ones and
twos. It's an old DJ term, okay? But now
we just kind of use it for producers and
the people who are pushing the buttons
and and moving the sliders and all those
different things and hitting the
commercials and controlling our
microphones. So yeah, when you hear me
say uh thanks to Nathan uh on the ones
and twos, actually here in a few
minutes, I'll say thanks to Brian on the
ones and twos who's been producing for
us. That's just an old an old DJ
turntable term uh from kind of the vinyl
mixer era that has been repurposed here
from modern times.
>> I always knew what it meant. I didn't
know where it came from again
411 thing.
>> Those old
>> going back an hour today. Matt learned
411 and ones and twos, baby.
>> I knew what everyone meant when they
when it came up, but I didn't know where
it came from.
>> Listen, you come for the football
education. You stay for the life lessons
education. you talk for three hours,
something's going to come up.
>> Bridge Burner brings up an interesting
point here. The last time there was a
replacement ref scenario in 2012, there
wasn't the current $30 billion plus of
legal wages placed in the NFL every
single season. I can't imagine seriously
botched calls are going to be popular in
that realm. I think with that amount of
money is has to have influence on this
situation. Do you agree? I think that's
a great point. I think it's a tremendous
point. And I also think the word legal
is important here, too.
>> Let's not pretend that there weren't
bets.
>> Oh, sure. But now it's everything's
sponsored by FanDuel and draftings and
the leagues have partners and the teams
have partners and
>> you might not get your knee brown
because of it, you know,
>> Tony might not be knocking on your door,
>> right? But more importantly are the
sponsors. I mean, these guys are putting
a lot of money in the league, too. So,
yes, they want the the outcomes of the
game to be as proper as possible.
>> Correct.
>> More now than ever, I would say.
>> Correct. R.J. tweets us, "In your guys'
opinions, what are the three must haves
for the Steelers by the time the draft
ends? Could be positions or capital for
next year.
>> At least a a wide receiver of note."
>> I would say wide receiver of note,
offensive lineman of note.
>> Yes, a left side, left guard, left
tackle, something.
>> My third thing might be a safety with
some speed.
Yeah, I think that's my third.
>> I would love to say better more draft
capital for next year, but again is I
just I don't know how realistic might
not be able to pull it off.
>> I don't know how realistic that is, but
what is realistic is
>> fifth for next year's fourth. Okay, but
that's not going to get George Banning.
>> It's true,
>> right?
>> Could get you Lenor Sers,
>> but no, I'm with you. I I think high-end
wide receiver, high-end offensive
lineman, get me a safety with some speed
on the back end in there, too. That
would be my list here as of today.
>> Yeah. Uh Pittsburgh Conversation tweets
us and says, "Does anyone have any
hunches where the Steelers will open the
first week of the season? I have a trip
planned to Pittsburgh. Rolling the dice
and already booked my hotel for week
one. Fingers crossed."
>> Well, I will say Pirates are not in town
that weekend, which helps the chance of
it being a home game. The Steelers have
also, I think, in like the last decade
only opened the season at home like
twice in the last 10 years or twice in
the last nine years.
>> That increases their chances. So, I
think that that's a good dice roll by
you Pittsburgh conversation.
>> Yeah. And if worst case scenario, you
have to come to Pittsburgh and hang out
with us, then do that.
>> That's right. We can we can share some
good spots for you to take in take in
the action. Uh let's see here. Uh Mattie
tweets and says, "I know Ton Green is
raw and probably a project, but his
tools are very intriguing. Do you guys
think the Steelers would have any
interest on him using a late round
pick?"
>> Yeah, except I think he's going to cost
a third.
>> You think so?
>> I think somebody's going to fall in love
with the trades. So here's
>> and traits is an interesting word. He's
really big and he's really fast.
>> Yeah.
>> But his quarterback traits
>> leave a lot to be desired.
>> Sure. Sure. Here's here's maybe
something, Matt, we could do in the back
half of the week when we're back at the
studio.
>> Let's talk about all these quarterbacks
not named Mendoza or Simpson. Okay.
>> And what's the highest round we think
they should or could be drafted in. Does
that sound like a fun exercise?
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Let's let's let's do that later.
>> Somebody might fall in love with what he
does. He's so much different than
everybody else.
>> Totally.
>> And I'm not paying that price.
Uh Joe tweets and says, "With the
evolution of NFL terminology, middle
linebacker is now offball linebacker.
Outside linebacker is now edge. Can we
look at a new name for tackles? They
don't tackle anyone."
>> Yeah.
>> He says, "How about a protector? How
about a mer?" Yeah, he could be left
protector, right protector. I get what
you're saying, but you know,
>> I always find it interesting that
there's an offensive tackle and a
defensive tackle tackle. At least one
side tackles uh actually makes tackles,
but that that's funny. You you guys are
funny.
last one here today. And I did this on
purpose. Matt CR Steeler Nation Chicago,
of course. You know, he's a regular
caller into SNR and Steelers
programming, but he does tweet from time
to time, too. He says, "My Steeler
brothers from another mother. You guys
are out in Phoenix. Have you seen Max
Starks? Isn't that his country?"
>> Oh, yeah. He walks by every couple
minutes.
>> It sure is. We've seen Max. I think
we're actually grabbing dinner with Max
tonight as well. And you know why I
wanted to save uh CR for last, too,
Matt?
>> Today is CR's birthday.
>> Ah, happy birthday. March 31st, 1945.
CR and I CR and I are friends on
Facebook. So I got that little, you
know, whose birthday it is notification.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Um, so what? 81 years old for CR if I
can do the math on that one.
>> Going strong. It sounds like
>> Steeler Nation Chicago, one of our one
of our loyalists here on SNR. Big happy
birthday to uh to CR. Matt, I think
that'll do it for the days proceedings.
>> Fine work, man.
>> I think that will do it for uh for our
three days. So plenty of people we have
to thank. Thanks to Nathan on Sunday and
Brian the past two days on the ones and
twos. Uh Jason, Emil, Nate, everybody
here on the Steelers video team that's
been making this possible uh for the
video element. Of course uh to TV for
putting everything back uh together uh
back in Western Pennsylvania. We'll be
excited to see TV again at the uh at the
end of this week.
>> I think he's missing us.
>> Get back in the studio with him. Uh, and
for our guests that we've had here, I
hope I don't forget anybody, but we had
Jeremy Fowler, we had Mike DeFabo, we
had Chris Alec, we had Chris Adamsky,
and we had Alan Saunders. I believe
those were the five that we had here uh
throughout the week. Thanks to those
guys for joining us as well. For Matt
Williamson, I'm Wes Schuler. Take care
everybody. Next time we talk to you, we
will be back in Pittsburgh and back on
East Coast time. And as always, you know
where to find us. It's on your 247 home
of the black and gold, Steelers Nation
Radio on the Steelers Audio Network.
>> What's up, NFL fans? The NFL draft is
finally here. And while you might not
know who your team is drafting this
year, you do know your watch party's
number one pick. Bud Light. The clean,
crisp taste that has all the scouts
talking. Guess that's why it's been the
group's go-to draft beer season after
season. Be sure to order around for the
table before your teams on the clock.
Bud Light. Easy to drink, easy to enjoy.
Enjoy responsibly. Annheiser Bush. Bud
Light beer. St. Louis, Missouri.